var questionsImport = [
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "It is best practice to use dry nitrogen to break the vacuum when dehydrating by the triple evacuation method. However, it:",
      "answers": [
         "often contains moisture.",
         "requires a minimum of 10 psig.",
         "is toxic when released into the atmosphere",
         "requires a pressure regulator"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "requires a pressure regulator"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Approved refrigerant recovery cylinders can be identified by which color code?",
      "answers": [
         "Gray tops and yellow bodies",
         "Blue tops and green bodies",
         "Yellow tops and gray bodies",
         "Green tops and gray bodies"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "Yellow tops and gray bodies"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "What type of synthetic oils are commonly used in new HFC systems and for retrofitting HCFC equipment to HFC refrigerants?",
      "answers": [
         "Polyolester",
         "Glycol",
         "Alkylbenzene",
         "Mineral Oil"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "Polyolester"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "When using nitrogen in repairing a sealed refrigeration system, what should the nitrogen tank always be equipped with?",
      "answers": [
         "Float sensor",
         "Regulator",
         "Red top",
         "Hand valve"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Regulator"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which of the following factors affect the speed of system dehydration?",
      "answers": [
         "The ambient temperature and the entropy of the refrigerant.",
         "The ambient temperature and amount of moisture in the system.",
         "The latent heat content of the refrigerant.",
         "The system superheat."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "The ambient temperature and amount of moisture in the system."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which of the following repairs would always be considered \"major\" under EPA's regulations?",
      "answers": [
         "Replacement of an evaporator coil.",
         "Replacement of a filter-drier.",
         "Replacement of a Schrader valve core.",
         "Replacement of a condenser fan motor."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "Replacement of an evaporator coil."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "When a pungent odor is detected during a sealed system recovery and/or repair which of the following is most likely?",
      "answers": [
         "The refrigerant should not be recovered.",
         "A compressor burnout has occurred.",
         "It is the characteristic smell of the refrigerant.",
         "The refrigerant should be vented."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "A compressor burnout has occurred."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which of the following best describes low loss fittings on refrigerant recovery devices used to recover CFCs, HCFCs, and HFCs?",
      "answers": [
         "They can be either manually closed or automatically closed when disconnected to prevent loss of refrigerant from hoses.",
         "They are used to connect the recovery device to an appliance and leak only small amounts of refrigerant during use.",
         "They are used to connect the recovery device to an appliance and must be discarded after each use.",
         "They eliminate oil loss during recovery."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "They can be either manually closed or automatically closed when disconnected to prevent loss of refrigerant from hoses."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "What is the state of the refrigerant leaving the receiver in a refrigeration system?",
      "answers": [
         "Low pressure liquid",
         "Low pressure vapor",
         "High pressure liquid",
         "High pressure vapor"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "High pressure liquid"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "What should be used to remove ice from sight glasses or viewing glasses?",
      "answers": [
         "Refrigerant",
         "An alcohol spray",
         "Water",
         "A screwdriver or flat file"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "An alcohol spray"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "In which component of a system does the refrigerant change from a high-pressure vapor to a high-pressure liquid?",
      "answers": [
         "Receiver",
         "Metering device",
         "Accumulator",
         "Condenser"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "Condenser"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "How should refrigerant cylinders be positioned when they are shipped?",
      "answers": [
         "Inverted",
         "Upright",
         "Horizontally",
         "Stacked"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Upright"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Why are some hydrofluoroolefin (HFO) refrigerants classified as \"A2L\"?",
      "answers": [
         "They have toxicity characteristics.",
         "They are less flammable than hydrocarbon refrigerants, but most are still mildly flammable",
         "They are prohibited for use in the U.S.",
         "They have high ozone depleting potentials and low global warming potentials."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "They are less flammable than hydrocarbon refrigerants, but most are still mildly flammable"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which of the following gases is used as the baseline measurement for global warming potential?",
      "answers": [
         "Ammonia",
         "Carbon Dioxide",
         "CFC-12",
         "Propane"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Carbon Dioxide"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "A very large refrigerant leak can cause suffocation because refrigerants:",
      "answers": [
         "smell strong and make breathing difficult.",
         "are lighter than air and cause dizziness.",
         "are heavier than air and displace oxygen",
         "sting the nose and cause sneezing."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "are heavier than air and displace oxygen"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "When evacuating a system, the use of a severely oversized vacuum pump could:",
      "answers": [
         "cause trapped oil to freeze.",
         "cause trapped refrigerant to freeze.",
         "cause trapped water to freeze.",
         "cause the valves to freeze."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "cause trapped water to freeze."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "What are the two factors that, if present, are most likely to lead to an explosion with hydrocarbon refrigerants?",
      "answers": [
         "A sufficient concentration of the refrigerant in the space and an ignition source.",
         "Electrical wiring and water.",
         "A leak from the system and airflow.",
         "Direct sunlight and warm temperatures."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "A sufficient concentration of the refrigerant in the space and an ignition source."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "After recovering refrigerant from a sealed system, if nitrogen is used to pressurize or blow debris out of the system, the nitrogen:",
      "answers": [
         "must be recovered.",
         "may be vented to the ambient air.",
         "should be returned to the cylinder.",
         "should only be used if mixed with R-22."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "may be vented to the ambient air."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which of the following are recommended safe work practices when recovering refrigerants?",
      "answers": [
         "Wear safety eyewear and butyl-lined gloves when connecting/disconnecting hoses.",
         "Wear a respirator when working with any refrigerant.",
         "Wear cotton gloves when working with any compressed gas.",
         "Ventilation is only necessary if oil, appearing as a white cloud or fog, is emitted during the recovery procedure."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "Wear safety eyewear and butyl-lined gloves when connecting/disconnecting hoses."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "What effect will low ambient temperatures have on recovery?",
      "answers": [
         "Shorten the recovery time.",
         "Increase the recovery time.",
         "Minimize emissions.",
         "Require frequent drier changes."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Increase the recovery time."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which of the following is true if a system will not hold a vacuum after it has been evacuated?",
      "answers": [
         "The system is ready to be charged.",
         "The system has been adequately evacuated.",
         "The system may be leaking.",
         "An expansion valve is clogged."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "The system may be leaking."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "How would you remove moisture from refrigerant in a system?",
      "answers": [
         "Purge the condenser.",
         "Drain the oil separator.",
         "Reduce water flow to the condenser.",
         "Use a filter drier."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "Use a filter drier."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which of the following statements about \"self-contained\" recovery devices is true?",
      "answers": [
         "They are evacuated cylinders capable of liquid transfer.",
         "They remove refrigerant from an appliance without the assistance of components in the appliance.",
         "They have a self-contained power source that requires periodic charging.",
         "They can only be used on air conditioning and refrigeration equipment containing less than 15 pounds of refrigerant."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "They remove refrigerant from an appliance without the assistance of components in the appliance."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which leak repair category does the EPA define as air-conditioning appliances used to provide cooling in order to control heat and/or humidity in occupied facilities including, but not limited to, residential, office, and commercial buildings?",
      "answers": [
         "Commercial refrigeration",
         "Industrial process refrigeration",
         "Comfort cooling",
         "ice making refrigeration"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "Comfort cooling"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "What does ozone depletion potential (or 'ODP') measure?",
      "answers": [
         "The ability of a substance to cause global warming.",
         "The ability of a substance to destroy ozone in the stratosphere.",
         "A rating of health hazards caused by ozone depletion.",
         "The length of time a refrigerant stays in the atmosphere."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "The ability of a substance to destroy ozone in the stratosphere."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which of the following refrigerant releases is considered a violation of the prohibition on venting?",
      "answers": [
         "Release of \"de minimis\" quantities in the course of making good faith attempts to recapture and recycle or safely dispose of refrigerant.",
         "Release of mixtures of nitrogen and refrigerant that result from adding nitrogen to a fully charged appliance to leak test the appliance.",
         "Refrigerants emitted in the course of normal operation of an appliance.",
         "Refrigerants emitted when connecting or disconnecting low loss hoses to charge or service an appliance."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Release of mixtures of nitrogen and refrigerant that result from adding nitrogen to a fully charged appliance to leak test the appliance."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "What is the service procedure if the refrigerant in a recovery cylinder is suspected to be contaminated?",
      "answers": [
         "Take a pressure reading of the cylinder",
         "Weigh the cylinder",
         "Discard the refrigerant",
         "Dilute the refrigerant with virgin refrigerant"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "Take a pressure reading of the cylinder"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Before beginning a refrigerant recovery procedure, it is ALWAYS necessary to:",
      "answers": [
         "allow the appliance to stabilize at room temperature.",
         "know the type of refrigerant that is in the system.",
         "remove the appliance to an outdoor location.",
         "disconnect the appliance from its power source."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "know the type of refrigerant that is in the system."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "What is the best use for testing with soap bubbles?",
      "answers": [
         "To pinpoint refrigerant leaks.",
         "To find refrigerant leaks in coil fin area.",
         "To detect leaks in water tube condensers.",
         "To detect leaks if the condenser is excessively dirty."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "To pinpoint refrigerant leaks."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "What is the component directly following the condenser in a refrigeration system using a thermal expansion valve?",
      "answers": [
         "Receiver",
         "Compressor",
         "Accumulator",
         "Evaporator"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "Receiver"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "What is the term for removing refrigerant in any condition from a system and storing it in an external container without necessarily testing or processing it in any way?",
      "answers": [
         "Recycling",
         "Recovery",
         "Reclaiming",
         "Restoring"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Recovery"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which type of refrigerant has the highest ozone depletion potential (ODP)?",
      "answers": [
         "HCFCS",
         "HFCs",
         "CFCs",
         "HFOS"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "CFCs"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "When an HFC system with POE oil has been opened for a major system repair, what is the minimum evacuation level that should be achieved before charging the system?",
      "answers": [
         "20 in Hg",
         "10 in of mercury",
         "500 microns",
         "25 in Hg"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "500 microns"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "What is the state of the refrigerant entering the compressor of a refrigeration system?",
      "answers": [
         "High pressure liquid",
         "High pressure vapor",
         "Low pressure liquid",
         "Low pressure vapor"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "Low pressure vapor"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "In what state should a system be to measure a final system vacuum?",
      "answers": [
         "With the gas ballast open.",
         "With the vacuum pump operating.",
         "With the system heated.",
         "With the system isolated and the vacuum pump turned off."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "With the system isolated and the vacuum pump turned off."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "What must be done before disposing of any appliance containing a CFC, HCFC, or HFC refrigerant?",
      "answers": [
         "Recover the refrigerant.",
         "Purge the appliance with nitrogen.",
         "Flush the appliance with R-134a.",
         "Seal the appliance so no refrigerant can escape."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "Recover the refrigerant."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "When corrosion is found within the body of a relief valve, the valve must be:",
      "answers": [
         "Repaired",
         "Reconditioned",
         "Cleaned",
         "Replaced"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "Replaced"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which of the following safety precautions should be adhered to for low-pressure systems?",
      "answers": [
         "Use gloves and safety goggles when working with liquid refrigerant.",
         "Reset the water freezestat after recharging.",
         "Shut down the compressor before removing the gauge from the low side of the system.",
         "Use a refrigerant leak detector before entering the mechanical room."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "Use gloves and safety goggles when working with liquid refrigerant."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "What is the Montreal Protocol?",
      "answers": [
         "An international treaty that addresses ozone-depleting substances and their alternatives.",
         "A test for energy efficiency adopted by the Canadian government.",
         "A procedure for measuring levels of CFCs in the atmosphere.",
         "A test for ozone concentration."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "An international treaty that addresses ozone-depleting substances and their alternatives."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which ASHRAE classification means slightly flammable?",
      "answers": [
         "A1",
         "A2L",
         "A3",
         "B1"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "A2L"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "What is the Significant New Alternatives Policy (SNAP) Program?",
      "answers": [
         "EPA's program that identifies refrigerants with lower overall risks to human health and the environment.",
         "Covers only CFC and HCFC refrigerants used in residential air conditioning.",
         "Relates to CFC and HCFC refrigerants used in commercial air conditioning.",
         "Covers only CFC and HCFC refrigerants used in industrial process refrigeration."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "EPA's program that identifies refrigerants with lower overall risks to human health and the environment."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "HFCs _______;",
      "answers": [
         "will not damage stratospheric ozone, but have a high GWP.",
         "will damage stratospheric ozone and have a low GWP.",
         "will not deplete stratospheric ozone and have a low GWP.",
         "are only harmful to ground level ozone."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "will not damage stratospheric ozone, but have a high GWP."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which international agreement (Treaty) regulated the production and use of CFCs, HCFCs, halons, methyl chloroform and carbon tetrachloride?",
      "answers": [
         "Kyoto Treaty",
         "Montreal Protocol",
         "Council of Nicaea",
         "Treaty of Ghent"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Montreal Protocol"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which of the following refrigerants is an HFO?",
      "answers": [
         "R-22",
         "R-134a",
         "R-410a",
         "R-1234ze"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "R-1234ze"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which of the following refrigerants has a GWP of \"1\"?",
      "answers": [
         "R-22",
         "R-134a",
         "R-410a",
         "CO2"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "CO2"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which of the following has the highest Ozone Depletion Potential?",
      "answers": [
         "HFOs",
         "HCFCs",
         "HFCs",
         "CFCs"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "CFCs"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "How much can a person be fined per day per violation for knowingly releasing a regulated substance that violates the Clean Air Act?",
      "answers": [
         "$10,000",
         "$25,000",
         "$37,000",
         "$44,539"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "$44,539"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "The low-side test-pressure data-plate value should be used by a technician to determine a safe pressure for:",
      "answers": [
         "recovering refrigerant.",
         "leak testing.",
         "refrigerant charging.",
         "retrofitting a system."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "leak testing."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Clean refrigerant for reuse by separating the oil from the refrigerant and removing moisture from the refrigerant by passing it through one or more filter driers, is the definition of;",
      "answers": [
         "Recover",
         "Reclaim",
         "Reuse",
         "Recycle"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "Recycle"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "The chlorine in CFCs and HCFCs;",
      "answers": [
         "will dissolve in water.",
         "will not dissolve in water.",
         "will rain out of the atmosphere.",
         "is heavier than air and cannot rise to the stratosphere."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "will not dissolve in water."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Recover any remaining refrigerant and then render the cylinder useless, then recycle the metal is the proper disposal method for;",
      "answers": [
         "Recovery cylinders",
         "One pound cans",
         "Disposable cylinders",
         "Accumulator cylinders"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "Disposable cylinders"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "The molecule found in CFCs and HCFCs that depletes ozone is:",
      "answers": [
         "Fluorine",
         "Hydrogen",
         "Carbon",
         "Chlorine"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "Chlorine"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "A single chlorine atom can destroy how many ozone molecules?",
      "answers": [
         "100",
         "1000",
         "10000",
         "100000"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "100000"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Silicone elastomers, for use in seals and gaskets, are not compatible with which refrigerants?",
      "answers": [
         "HCFCs",
         "CFCs",
         "HFOs",
         "HFCS"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "HFOs"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Reusable refrigerant containers under high-pressure must be hydrostatically tested how often?",
      "answers": [
         "1 year",
         "3 years",
         "5 years",
         "7 years"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "5 years"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "HCFCs contain;",
      "answers": [
         "Chlorine, Fluorine, and Carbon",
         "Hydrogen, Chlorine, Fluorine, and Carbon",
         "Hydrogen, Fluorine, and Carbon",
         "Hydrogen, Fluorine, and Olefin"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Hydrogen, Chlorine, Fluorine, and Carbon"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "To process refrigerant to a level equal to new (virgin) product specifications as determined by chemical analysis defines;",
      "answers": [
         "Recovery",
         "Reclaiming",
         "Reuse",
         "Recycle"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Reclaiming"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Crop loss, eye disease, and skin cancer have been attributed to;",
      "answers": [
         "Depletion of Stratospheric nitrogen",
         "Depletion of Stratospheric chlorine monoxide",
         "Depletion of Stratospheric ozone",
         "Depletion of Stratospheric oxygen"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "Depletion of Stratospheric ozone"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Before shipping any used refrigerant cylinders, check that the cylinder meets what standards:",
      "answers": [
         "Department of Transportation",
         "The Significant New Alternatives Policy (SNAP)",
         "Underwriters Laboratories",
         "All of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "Department of Transportation"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "The compressor __________",
      "answers": [
         "changes a high-pressure vapor to a high-pressure liquid.",
         "changes a low-pressure vapor to a high-pressure vapor.",
         "changes a high-pressure liquid to a low-pressure liquid.",
         "changes a low-pressure liquid to a low-pressure vapor."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "changes a low-pressure vapor to a high-pressure vapor."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "The condenser __________",
      "answers": [
         "changes a high-pressure vapor to a high-pressure liquid.",
         "changes a low-pressure vapor to a low-pressure liquid.",
         "changes a high-pressure liquid to a low-pressure liquid.",
         "changes a low-pressure liquid to a low-pressure vapor."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "changes a high-pressure vapor to a high-pressure liquid."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "A refrigerant cylinder designed to hold recovered refrigerant has a:",
      "answers": [
         "yellow body and grey top.",
         "grey body and yellow top.",
         "green body and yellow top.",
         "orange body and grey top."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "grey body and yellow top."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "An ozone molecule contains;",
      "answers": [
         "One oxygen atom",
         "Two oxygen atoms",
         "Three oxygen atoms",
         "Four oxygen atoms"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "Three oxygen atoms"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which type of refrigerant contains no chlorine?",
      "answers": [
         "HCFCs",
         "HCFC Blends",
         "HFCs",
         "CFCs"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "HFCs"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Refrigeration technicians who violate the Clean Air Act can:",
      "answers": [
         "lose their EPA certification.",
         "be fined.",
         "be required to appear in Federal court.",
         "all of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "all of the above"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "After 1995, any supplies of CFC refrigerant to service existing units in the USA can only come from:",
      "answers": [
         "recovery and recycling.",
         "solvent conversion.",
         "European chemical manufacturers.",
         "Third World chemical manufacturers."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "recovery and recycling."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Refrigerant that is recovered can be returned to:",
      "answers": [
         "the same system or other systems owned by the same person without restriction.",
         "used in any system serviced that day",
         "Sold as used refrigerant to other customers.",
         "Called Reclaimed if a filter-drier was used during recovery."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "the same system or other systems owned by the same person without restriction."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Refrigerant can not be called \"reclaimed\" unless it:",
      "answers": [
         "was processed in a reclaiming machine.",
         "has been chemically analyzed and the refrigerant meets the ARI-700 purity standard.",
         "is recovered from a system less than 1 year old.",
         "is recovered from a system still under warranty."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "has been chemically analyzed and the refrigerant meets the ARI-700 purity standard."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "The EPA can require a technician to demonstrate their ability to perform proper procedures for recovering and/or recycling refrigerant. Failure to demonstrate competency can result in:",
      "answers": [
         "revocation of the technician's certification.",
         "seizure of the technician's recovery or recycling equipment.",
         "seizure of any refrigerant purchased by the technician which is still in his/her possession.",
         "mandatory attendance at a refrigerant training camp."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "revocation of the technician's certification."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "What characteristic(s) of CFCs make them more likely to reach the stratosphere than most other compounds containing chlorine?",
      "answers": [
         "Refrigerants that contain chlorine but not hydrogen are so stable that they do not break down in the lower atmosphere after being released. The chlorine or bromine reacts with ozone, causing it to change back to oxygen, thus destroying the ozone layer.",
         "CFCs are lighter than other damaging compounds, making it easier for them to float upward when released.",
         "CFCs are attracted to the static in the atmosphere.",
         "CFCs are attracted to dust in the atmosphere."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "Refrigerants that contain chlorine but not hydrogen are so stable that they do not break down in the lower atmosphere after being released. The chlorine or bromine reacts with ozone, causing it to change back to oxygen, thus destroying the ozone layer."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "A system is considered dehydrated when:",
      "answers": [
         "the vacuum indicator shows you have reached and held the required finished vacuum.",
         "the vacuum pump has run at least 7 hours.",
         "the manifold suction gauge has held a 30 in. hg./760 mm vacuum for 3 hours.",
         "you are ready to leave for the day."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "the vacuum indicator shows you have reached and held the required finished vacuum."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Disposable refrigerant containers are used for _______ refrigerant.",
      "answers": [
         "recycled",
         "recovered",
         "virgin",
         "both a and b"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "virgin"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which refrigerant is an HCFC?",
      "answers": [
         "R-124",
         "R-134a",
         "R-410A",
         "R-12"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "R-124"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "What statement is true about an azeotropic refrigerant mixture?",
      "answers": [
         "It is always make from just two components.",
         "It has a pressure-temperature curve identical to one of its components.",
         "It is a mixture that is always made from at least three component refrigerants.",
         "It is a mixture that acts like a single-component refrigerant over its entire range."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "It is a mixture that acts like a single-component refrigerant over its entire range."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Chlorofluorocarbons (CFCs) and hydrochlorofluorocarbons (HCFCs) have which of the following in common?",
      "answers": [
         "They have identical ODP's.",
         "They both contain hydrogen.",
         "They have the same normal boiling points.",
         "They must be recovered before opening or disposing of appliances."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "They must be recovered before opening or disposing of appliances."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "To scrap a disposable cylinder, the internal cylinder pressure should be reduced to at least:",
      "answers": [
         "0 psig.",
         "15 psig.",
         "20 psig.",
         "28.8 psig."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "0 psig."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Manifold gauge sets are often color coded, when this is done, the high pressure gauge is color coded:",
      "answers": [
         "red.",
         "white.",
         "blue.",
         "yellow."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "red."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "In general, blended refrigerants should be charged:",
      "answers": [
         "as a vapor.",
         "at very high temperatures.",
         "as a liquid.",
         "the same as any other refrigerant."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "as a liquid."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Blended refrigerants leak from a system:",
      "answers": [
         "faster than other refrigerants.",
         "in uneven amounts due to different vapor pressures.",
         "slower than other refrigerants.",
         "only if the joint fails completely."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "in uneven amounts due to different vapor pressures."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which of the following gases help form the earth's protective shield?",
      "answers": [
         "Chlorine",
         "Chlorides",
         "Carbon Monoxide",
         "Stratospheric Ozone"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "Stratospheric Ozone"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "In a refrigeration system, the device that changes a low pressure vapor to a high pressure vapor is the:",
      "answers": [
         "evaporator.",
         "expansion device.",
         "compressor.",
         "condenser."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "compressor."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Data shows that chlorine in the stratosphere comes mainly from CFCs rather than from natural sources such as volcanoes because:",
      "answers": [
         "The rise in the amount of chlorine in the stratosphere matches the rise in the amount of fluorine, which has different natural sources than chlorine.",
         "The rise in the amount of chlorine in the stratosphere matches the rise in CFC emissions.",
         "Air samples taken from the stratosphere over erupting volcanoes show that volcanoes contribute a small quantity of chlorine to the stratosphere when compared to CFCs.",
         "All of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "All of the above"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which atom of the CFC molecule causes ozone depletion?",
      "answers": [
         "fluorine",
         "chlorine",
         "sodium",
         "helium"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "chlorine"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "The ozone layer protects the earth from:",
      "answers": [
         "nuclear radiation.",
         "infrared radiation.",
         "ultraviolet radiation from the sun.",
         "bacteria from space."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "ultraviolet radiation from the sun."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "When using with any solvent, cleaner, chemical or refrigerant, you should review:",
      "answers": [
         "moisture solubility information.",
         "chemical compound reference sheets.",
         "material safety data sheets.",
         "chemical composition reference sheets."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "material safety data sheets."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "An award of up to what amount may be paid to a person supplying information that leads to a penalty against a technician who is intentionally venting?",
      "answers": [
         "$5,000",
         "$10,000",
         "$27,000",
         "$37,000"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "$10,000"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "The Montreal Protocol is:",
      "answers": [
         "an energy efficiency test developed by the Canadian government.",
         "a test procedure for measuring the level of chlorine in the stratosphere.",
         "a procedure or protocol to test for ozone concentration in the atmosphere.",
         "a treaty among nations that controls production of CFC's and HCFC's."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "a treaty among nations that controls production of CFC's and HCFC's."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "What is one of the most serious results of damage to the ozone layer?",
      "answers": [
         "mutations of marine plants",
         "increased volcanic activity",
         "increases in human skin cancer",
         "higher natural background radioactivity"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "increases in human skin cancer"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Of the refrigerants listed below, which has the lowest ozone depletion potential?",
      "answers": [
         "R-22",
         "R-11",
         "R-12",
         "R-113"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "R-22"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "To determine the maximum allowable pressure to use when checking a system, check:",
      "answers": [
         "with the equipment owner.",
         "with the refrigerant pressure/temperature tables.",
         "the design pressure on the equipment nameplate",
         "ask the local utility company."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "the design pressure on the equipment nameplate"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Ozone depletion potential, or \"ODP,\" is:",
      "answers": [
         "Always equal to twice the global warming potential, or \"GWP.\"",
         "A absolute rating of the health hazard caused by ozone depletion.",
         "A measure of the ability of CFCs' and HCFCs' to destroy ozone.",
         "A rating for ground level smog pollution."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "A measure of the ability of CFCs' and HCFCs' to destroy ozone."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "An example of an HFC refrigerant is:",
      "answers": [
         "R-12.",
         "R-22.",
         "R-123.",
         "R-134a."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "R-134a."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Whenever dry nitrogen from a portable cylinder is connected to a system, what item is of most importance in consideration of safety?",
      "answers": [
         "The regulator has a new set of gauges.",
         "The pressure gauges are clean.",
         "There is a relief valve in the downstream line from the pressure regulator.",
         "No refrigerant lines can leak."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "There is a relief valve in the downstream line from the pressure regulator."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "During servicing of a refrigeration system containing R-12, the refrigerant must be:",
      "answers": [
         "recovered.",
         "recovered and replaced with R-134a, no exceptions!",
         "vented.",
         "destroyed."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "recovered."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which safety precaution(s) should always be followed:",
      "answers": [
         "Never apply an open flame to a refrigerant cylinder.",
         "Never cut or weld any refrigerant line when refrigerant is in the line.",
         "Never use oxygen to purge lines or to pressurize a system.",
         "all of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "all of the above"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "In a vapor compression refrigeration system, cooling occurs when:",
      "answers": [
         "refrigerant liquid turns to a vapor.",
         "refrigerant vapor turns to a liquid.",
         "the refrigerant is under maximum pressure.",
         "the refrigerant gives off heat."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "refrigerant liquid turns to a vapor."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "The evacuation of a system is a method of:",
      "answers": [
         "pinpointing the location of leaks.",
         "acid removal.",
         "dehydration.",
         "all of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "dehydration."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Each chlorine atom in the stratosphere can destroy ____ ozone molecules.",
      "answers": [
         "100",
         "1,000",
         "10,000",
         "100,000"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "100,000"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "An example of a HFC refrigerant is:",
      "answers": [
         "R-11",
         "R-124",
         "R-142b",
         "R-410A"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "R-410A"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which gas(es) would cause the LEAST damage to the environment during a leak check?",
      "answers": [
         "dry nitrogen and R-22",
         "dry nitrogen and R-12",
         "compressed air and R-12",
         "dry nitrogen"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "dry nitrogen"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Refrigerant migrates to the compressor crankcase because of a difference in __________ between the refrigerant and the oil.",
      "answers": [
         "vapor pressure",
         "acidity",
         "volume",
         "density"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "vapor pressure"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "It is important not to mix R-22 and R-410A refrigerants in the same container because:",
      "answers": [
         "the mixture may be impossible to reclaim.",
         "the mixture will explode.",
         "the mixture is corrosive.",
         "they use different oils."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "the mixture may be impossible to reclaim."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "When using recovery unit, the fill level of the recovery tank can be controlled by:",
      "answers": [
         "a mechanical float switch.",
         "an electronic shut-off device.",
         "weight.",
         "all of the above."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "all of the above."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which of the following refrigerant releases is a violation of the EPA prohibition on venting?",
      "answers": [
         "release of \"de minimis\" quantities in the course of making good faith attempts to recover refrigerant",
         "release of mixtures of nitrogen and refrigerant that result from adding nitrogen to a fully charged appliance to \"leak-check\" the appliance",
         "refrigerants emitted in the course of normal operation of an appliance",
         "de minimis refrigerants vented when connecting or disconnecting self-sealing hoses to charge a unit."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "release of mixtures of nitrogen and refrigerant that result from adding nitrogen to a fully charged appliance to \"leak-check\" the appliance"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which of the following human health effects could result from an increase in ultraviolet radiation?",
      "answers": [
         "an increase in cataracts cases",
         "an increase in male infertility cases",
         "an increase in heat prostration with the elderly",
         "an increase in the number of thyroid disorders"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "an increase in cataracts cases"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Never use an open flame to heat a refrigerant tank because:",
      "answers": [
         "it can result in venting refrigerant to the atmosphere.",
         "the tank may explode, causing serious injury to people nearby.",
         "refrigerant in the tank may decompose, forming a toxic material.",
         "all of the above."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "all of the above."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "When transporting cylinders containing used refrigerant, the DOT requires that you:",
      "answers": [
         "use OSHA-approved containers.",
         "attach DOT classification tags.",
         "ship by EPA certified carrier.",
         "do all of the above."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "attach DOT classification tags."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "According to ASHRAE's 1992 refrigerant safety classification, which of the following designations would be the most safe?",
      "answers": [
         "A-1",
         "A-3",
         "B-1",
         "B-3"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "A-1"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "The over-evacuation of a system:",
      "answers": [
         "can cause tube, condenser and/or evaporator collapse.",
         "damages vacuum gauge sets.",
         "causes vacuum pump damage.",
         "does not occur."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "does not occur."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Equipment covered by EPA regulations include:",
      "answers": [
         "only refrigerators and freezers using CFCs.",
         "only air-conditioning and refrigeration equipment containing and using HCFC refrigerants.",
         "all air-conditioning and refrigeration equipment using CFC, HCFC or HFC refrigerants.",
         "only commercial air-conditioning and refrigeration equipment made in the USA."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "all air-conditioning and refrigeration equipment using CFC, HCFC or HFC refrigerants."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Never overfill refrigerant storage cylinders because:",
      "answers": [
         "the cylinder may be too heavy to carry.",
         "the internal pressure of the cylinders may rise in heated areas and cause an explosion.",
         "some refrigerant may be vented as the cylinder valve is closed.",
         "the extra space in the cylinder might be needed for the next job."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "the internal pressure of the cylinders may rise in heated areas and cause an explosion."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "It is important not to mix different refrigerants in the same container because:",
      "answers": [
         "the mixture may be impossible to reclaim.",
         "the mixture will explode.",
         "the refrigerant mixture might be toxic.",
         "it violates EPA environmental regulations."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "the mixture may be impossible to reclaim."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Manifold gauge sets are often color coded, when this is done, the low pressure gauge is color coded:",
      "answers": [
         "red.",
         "white.",
         "blue.",
         "yellow."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "blue."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "All devices used for refrigerant recovery must:",
      "answers": [
         "be portable and weigh less than 100 pounds.",
         "contain a heavy-duty ozone shield.",
         "have a 5 Ton-refrigeration rating at 100F.",
         "meet EPA standards."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "meet EPA standards."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Reusable refrigerant containers that are normally under any pressure above 15 psig, must be hydrostatically tested and date stamped every:",
      "answers": [
         "1 year",
         "2 years",
         "3 years",
         "5 years"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "5 years"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which refrigerant(s) must be recovered before opening a system or disposing of a system?",
      "answers": [
         "R-410A",
         "R-407C",
         "R-134a",
         "all refrigerants must be recovered"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "all refrigerants must be recovered"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "To obtain an accurate vacuum readings during system evacuation, the system vacuum gauge should be located:",
      "answers": [
         "at the pump discharge.",
         "as far from the vacuum pump as possible.",
         "directly at the pump suction.",
         "anywhere in the evacuation service hose."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "as far from the vacuum pump as possible."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "What is the best proof that CFCs are in the stratosphere?",
      "answers": [
         "the theory of some professors in California",
         "measurement of CFCs in smog",
         "measurement of CFCs in air samples from the stratosphere",
         "measurement of other man-made compounds in air samples from the stratosphere"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "measurement of CFCs in air samples from the stratosphere"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "The recovery of refrigerants is necessary to:",
      "answers": [
         "maintain adequate supplies for service calls after the production bans.",
         "prevent the venting of refrigerants to the atmosphere.",
         "prevent stratospheric ozone depletion.",
         "all of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "all of the above"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "A compound pressure gauge, typically used on the low side of the system, measures pressure in:",
      "answers": [
         "psia.",
         "torrs and microns.",
         "psig and inches of mercury.",
         "psia and microns."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "psig and inches of mercury."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "_____________ refers to the process of cleaning refrigerant by oil separation and single or multiple passes through filter-driers, which reduce moisture and acidity?",
      "answers": [
         "recycling",
         "recovering",
         "reclaiming",
         "restoring"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "recycling"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "The high pressure gauge on service manifold sets has a continuous scale, usually calibrated to read from:",
      "answers": [
         "200 microns to 0 psi.",
         "0 to 250 psi.",
         "0 to 500 psi.",
         "200 psi to 750 psi."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "0 to 500 psi."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "________ is the process that returns refrigerant to new-product specifications and that requires chemical analysis?",
      "answers": [
         "recovery",
         "recycle",
         "reclaim",
         "reprocess"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "reclaim"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "A cylinder with a gray body and a yellow top indicates that the cylinder is designed to hold:",
      "answers": [
         "nitrogen.",
         "inert gas.",
         "only R-12.",
         "recovered refrigerant."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "recovered refrigerant."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "HCFC refrigerants:",
      "answers": [
         "are more harmful to stratospheric ozone than CFCs.",
         "do not damage stratospheric ozone at in any way.",
         "are less harmful to stratospheric ozone than CFCs.",
         "are more harmful than bromide containing compounds."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "are less harmful to stratospheric ozone than CFCs."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which type of refrigerant is the most harmful to stratospheric ozone?",
      "answers": [
         "Refrigerants containing Bromine",
         "Refrigerants containing Chlorine",
         "Refrigerants containing Hydrogen",
         "Refrigerants containing Fluoride"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "Refrigerants containing Bromine"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "According to the EPA, a _________ leak detection methods is considered to be the most effective for locating the general area of a small leak.",
      "answers": [
         "standing vacuum test",
         "electronic or ultrasonic tester",
         "halide torch",
         "audible sound"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "electronic or ultrasonic tester"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Long hoses between the unit and the recovery machine should not be used because they cause:",
      "answers": [
         "excessive pressure drop.",
         "increased recovery time.",
         "increased emissions.",
         "all of the above."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "all of the above."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Recovery equipment that relies upon the compressor in the system would be considered:",
      "answers": [
         "system-dependent.",
         "self-contained.",
         "system independent.",
         "self-sufficient."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "system-dependent."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "A hermetic compressor must never be operated when:",
      "answers": [
         "the compressor is operating under light load.",
         "the compressor is operating under full load.",
         "there is a dehydration vacuum in the system.",
         "the outdoor temperature is above 125F."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "there is a dehydration vacuum in the system."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Self-contained recovery devices:",
      "answers": [
         "are evacuated recovery cylinders capable of liquid transfer.",
         "can capture liquid and/or vapor refrigerant without the assistance of components in the air- conditioning or refrigeration equipment.",
         "have a self-contained power source that requires recharging or battery replacement.",
         "can only be used on air-conditioning and refrigeration equipment containing less than 15 pounds of refrigerant."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "can capture liquid and/or vapor refrigerant without the assistance of components in the air- conditioning or refrigeration equipment."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Systems charged with R-410A should be leak checked with:",
      "answers": [
         "CFCs.",
         "HCFCs.",
         "pressurized nitrogen.",
         "compressed dry air."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "pressurized nitrogen."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "R-410A is not a typical blended refrigerant because:",
      "answers": [
         "It is a near azeotropic refrigerant.",
         "It can be charged as either a liquid or vapor.",
         "While it has a 400 series refrigerant number it behaves like a 500 series refrigerant.",
         "All of the above are true."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "All of the above are true."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "A ternary refrigerant blend is a ____ part mixture.",
      "answers": [
         "two-part",
         "three-part",
         "four-part",
         "five-part"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "three-part"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "In a refrigeration system, high pressure vapor is converted to high pressure liquid in the:",
      "answers": [
         "liquid receiver.",
         "TXV.",
         "suction line accumulator.",
         "condenser."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "condenser."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which of the following is an approved \"drop-in\" service replacement for R-12?",
      "answers": [
         "HFC-134a",
         "HFC-410A",
         "R-407C",
         "According to the EPA there are no \"drop-in\" replacements"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "According to the EPA there are no \"drop-in\" replacements"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "The proper method of discarding a disposable refrigerant cylinder is to:",
      "answers": [
         "bleed refrigerant to ambient and throw the cylinder into a commercial trash dumpster.",
         "assure that all refrigerant is recovered and that the cylinder is rendered useless, then recycle the metal.",
         "refill the cylinder a second time at an approved facility.",
         "giving the cylinder to a friend to be used as a compressed air tank."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "assure that all refrigerant is recovered and that the cylinder is rendered useless, then recycle the metal."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "CFC refrigerants are so named because they contain the elements:",
      "answers": [
         "chlorine, fluorine, carbon",
         "chlorine, fluorine, calcium",
         "carbon, fluoride, calcium",
         "chlorine, fluorine, hydrogen"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "chlorine, fluorine, carbon"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Before you dispose of any system containing a refrigerant, you must:",
      "answers": [
         "recover the refrigerant.",
         "purge the system with nitrogen.",
         "flush the system with R-11 or R-113.",
         "seal the system so no refrigerant can during disposal."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "recover the refrigerant."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "According to EPA regulations, which of the following is procedures is not an approved technique for system cleanup after a burnout?",
      "answers": [
         "installing a suction-line filter-drier",
         "flushing with liquid refrigerant to clean tubing",
         "triple evacuation",
         "deep vacuum evacuation"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "flushing with liquid refrigerant to clean tubing"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "When using nitrogen to pressurize a system, you should always:",
      "answers": [
         "Charge nitrogen as a liquid.",
         "Charge through a pressure regulator.",
         "Pressurize to above 1000 pounds.",
         "Never use nitrogen inside the system."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Charge through a pressure regulator."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "What effects can ozone depletion have on the environment?",
      "answers": [
         "reduced crop yields",
         "reduced marine life",
         "increased ground-level ozone",
         "all of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "all of the above"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Non-Azeotropic refrigerants leak from a system:",
      "answers": [
         "faster than other refrigerants.",
         "in uneven amounts due to different vapor pressures.",
         "slower than other refrigerants.",
         "only if the joint fails completely."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "in uneven amounts due to different vapor pressures."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "An example of an HCFC refrigerant is:",
      "answers": [
         "R-410A",
         "R-22",
         "R-114",
         "R-717"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "R-22"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which chemicals are controlled by the Montreal Protocol?",
      "answers": [
         "chlorofluorocarbons",
         "hydrochlorofluorocarbons",
         "halons",
         "all of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "all of the above"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Systems charged with R-134a should be leak checked with:",
      "answers": [
         "CFCs.",
         "HCFCs.",
         "compressed dry air.",
         "pressurized nitrogen."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "pressurized nitrogen."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "When evacuating a system, the hoses should be:",
      "answers": [
         "orange in color for safety reasons.",
         "as long as possible.",
         "smaller than vacuum pump inlet connection.",
         "equal to or larger than vacuum pump inlet connection."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "equal to or larger than vacuum pump inlet connection."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "It has been illegal to vent substitutes for CFC and HCFC refrigerants since:",
      "answers": [
         "June 1, 1992.",
         "July 15, 1993.",
         "November 1993.",
         "November 1995."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "November 1995."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Never use oxygen or compressed air to pressurize a system because:",
      "answers": [
         "when mixed with compressor oil or some refrigerants, it could explode.",
         "leaking oxygen or compressed air are more difficult to detect than nitrogen.",
         "the pressures produced by either oxygen or compressed air are not as good as nitrogen pressures.",
         "oxygen and compressed air do not mix with refrigerants."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "when mixed with compressor oil or some refrigerants, it could explode."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Refrigerant cylinders should always be:",
      "answers": [
         "free of rust and damage.",
         "color coded to indicate the contents.",
         "secure.",
         "all of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "all of the above"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Even though R-22 is considered non-toxic, it:",
      "answers": [
         "is lighter than air.",
         "can cause asphyxia.",
         "is a Class I refrigerant.",
         "can be detected by its color."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "can cause asphyxia."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "A system is dehydrated to:",
      "answers": [
         "remove oil and oil vapor.",
         "remove water and water vapor.",
         "remove refrigerant and refrigerant vapor.",
         "none of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "remove water and water vapor."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "According to the EPA, of the refrigerants listed below, which types of refrigerants will not contribute to Global Warming?",
      "answers": [
         "CFCs",
         "HCFCs",
         "HFCs",
         "They all contribute to Global Warming"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "They all contribute to Global Warming"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "The type of oil that is most commonly used in stationary air conditioning applications with HFC-410A refrigerant is:",
      "answers": [
         "ester oil.",
         "alkylbenzene oil.",
         "mineral oil.",
         "all oils are compatible with HFC-410A."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "ester oil."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Technicians receiving a passing grade on the Type II (medium-pressure, high-pressure and very high pressure) exam are certified to recover refrigerant during the maintenance, service, or repair of medium- and high-pressure equipment and very high pressure refrigerants, including:",
      "answers": [
         "CFC-13.",
         "HFC-410A.",
         "CFC-503.",
         "With Type II certification, you are certified for all very high pressure refrigerants including CFC- 13 and CFC-503."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "With Type II certification, you are certified for all very high pressure refrigerants including CFC- 13 and CFC-503."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Personal protective equipment (gloves, safety glasses, safety shoes, etc.) should always be worn is when:",
      "answers": [
         "reporting for work.",
         "handling and filling refrigerant cylinders.",
         "climbing ladders.",
         "lifting."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "handling and filling refrigerant cylinders."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Refrigerant vapors or mist should not be inhaled because:",
      "answers": [
         "they are addictive.",
         "they can lower the body's core temperature.",
         "they may cause skin cancer.",
         "they may cause heart irregularities and/or unconsciousness."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "they may cause heart irregularities and/or unconsciousness."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Of the items listed below, which is (are) violation(s) of the Clean Air Act?",
      "answers": [
         "falsifying or failing to keep required records",
         "failing to reach required evacuation levels before opening or disposing of appliances",
         "knowingly releasing CFC or HCFC refrigerants or their substitutes while repairing appliances",
         "all of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "all of the above"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "HFC refrigerants contain:",
      "answers": [
         "helium, fluorine, carbon.",
         "helium, fluorine, calcium.",
         "hydrogen, fluorine, chlorine.",
         "hydrogen, fluorine, carbon."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "hydrogen, fluorine, carbon."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which refrigerant contains an HCFC?",
      "answers": [
         "R-12",
         "R-22",
         "R-134a",
         "R-410A"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "R-22"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Recovery equipment that relies upon the pressure of the refrigerant in the appliance would be considered:",
      "answers": [
         "system-dependent.",
         "self-contained.",
         "illegal.",
         "self-sufficient."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "system-dependent."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Refrigerant that enters the compressor, under normal operating conditions, is a:",
      "answers": [
         "low pressure vapor.",
         "low pressure liquid.",
         "high pressure liquid",
         "high pressure vapor."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "low pressure vapor."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "It is necessary to place a refrigerant label on:",
      "answers": [
         "a refrigerant cylinder which is being returned for reclaiming.",
         "a cylinder to identify the pressure.",
         "a truck to identify cylinder hauler.",
         "cylinder to identify gross weight."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "a refrigerant cylinder which is being returned for reclaiming."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which refrigerant contains a CFC?",
      "answers": [
         "R-500",
         "R-410A",
         "R-134a",
         "R-123"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "R-500"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Use __________ to remove ice from a sight glass.",
      "answers": [
         "an alcohol spray",
         "water",
         "R-11 refrigerant",
         "a screwdriver or flat file"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "an alcohol spray"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "According to the EPA, an oil sample should be taken for which of the following reasons?",
      "answers": [
         "A new filter-drier has been installed.",
         "The system had a leak or a major component failure.",
         "The system is not cooling properly.",
         "Recycled refrigerant was added to the system."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "The system had a leak or a major component failure."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "The EPA requires the installation of a service aperture or process stub on all appliances using a class I or class II substance as a refrigerant. The main purpose of this requirement is to make it easier to:",
      "answers": [
         "recover refrigerant.",
         "change the compressor lubrication.",
         "vent non-condensables.",
         "dehydrate the system."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "recover refrigerant."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Recycling and recovery equipment intended for use with air-conditioning and refrigeration equipment (except for small appliances) must be tested under:",
      "answers": [
         "ARI 700",
         "ARI 740",
         "EPA 700",
         "UL 740"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "ARI 740"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Refrigerant entering the compressor of a refrigeration system is a:",
      "answers": [
         "liquid",
         "subcooled liquid",
         "subcooled vapor",
         "superheated vapor"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "superheated vapor"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "What is being done in the U.S. to stop damage to the stratospheric ozone layer?",
      "answers": [
         "replacing coal fired power plants for the production of electricity",
         "capturing and ultimately eliminating use of chlorofluorocarbons",
         "enforcing strict emission requirements on garbage incinerators",
         "all of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "capturing and ultimately eliminating use of chlorofluorocarbons"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "The type of oil that is most commonly used in stationary refrigeration applications with HFC-134a refrigerant is:",
      "answers": [
         "ester oil.",
         "alkylbenzene oil.",
         "mineral oil.",
         "all oils are compatible with HFC-134a."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "ester oil."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "The term used to describe the fact that a refrigerant blend has a range of boiling or condensing points at a constant pressure is:",
      "answers": [
         "pressure slide.",
         "mixture slump.",
         "fractionation.",
         "temperature glide."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "temperature glide."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Under EPA's regulations, what standard must reclaimed refrigerant meet before it can be resold?",
      "answers": [
         "ARI 700",
         "ARI 740",
         "EPA 700",
         "UL 740"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "ARI 700"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "It is illegal to:",
      "answers": [
         "use CFC refrigerants.",
         "manufacture or import HFC refrigerants into the U.S.",
         "knowingly release any refrigerant during the service, maintenance, repair or disposal of appliances, with the exception of de minimis releases.",
         "do any of the above."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "knowingly release any refrigerant during the service, maintenance, repair or disposal of appliances, with the exception of de minimis releases."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Refrigerant that enters the expansion or throttling device (also known as the metering device)is a:",
      "answers": [
         "saturated vapor.",
         "superheated vapor.",
         "mixture of vapor and liquid.",
         "liquid."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "liquid."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which of the following statements would be considered good service practices for conserving refrigerant?",
      "answers": [
         "recover or recycle refrigerant",
         "keep systems tight",
         "find and repair leaks",
         "all of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "all of the above"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Under the EPA \"safe disposal requirements\", the person responsible for making sure that the refrigerant has been removed from household refrigerators before they are disposed of is the:",
      "answers": [
         "final person in the disposal chain",
         "service technician worked on the equipment last",
         "the manager of the service company that last serviced the equipment",
         "the EPA field inspectors"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "final person in the disposal chain"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which refrigerant listed below is a \"low-pressure refrigerant\" under EPA's refrigerant recycling regulations?",
      "answers": [
         "R-22",
         "R-123",
         "R-134a",
         "R-500"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "R-123"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "When moisture exists in an operating system, which of the following is the most likely to occur?",
      "answers": [
         "Copper tubes and fittings will rust.",
         "Compressor discharge valves will freeze up.",
         "Acid will form.",
         "Compressor head pressures will rise."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "Acid will form."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which of the following is a \"very high-pressure refrigerant\" under EPA's refrigerant recycling regulations?",
      "answers": [
         "R-22",
         "R-134a",
         "R-13",
         "R-500"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "R-13"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "When using nitrogen to pressurize a system, you should:",
      "answers": [
         "only charge with nitrogen vapor.",
         "never use a pressure regulator.",
         "never use a pressure relief valve",
         "always charge to at least 1000 psig."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "only charge with nitrogen vapor."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "We dealing with small systems, how many different refrigerants may be recovered into the same cylinder?",
      "answers": [
         "only one.",
         "only two.",
         "any number as long as all are CFCs.",
         "depends on the reclaim company."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "only one."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "When operating refrigerant recovery or recycling equipment, the following precautions should always be followed.",
      "answers": [
         "wear safety glasses",
         "wear protective gloves",
         "follow all safety precautions for the equipment",
         "all of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "all of the above"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Of the refrigerants listed below, which types of refrigerants will not damage stratospheric ozone?",
      "answers": [
         "CFCs",
         "HCFCs",
         "HFCs",
         "They all damage the ozone"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "HFCs"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Refrigerant leaves the condenser of an operating system as a:",
      "answers": [
         "low pressure liquid.",
         "low pressure vapor.",
         "high pressure liquid.",
         "high pressure vapor."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "high pressure liquid."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "If corrosion is found within the body of a relief valve, the valve must be:",
      "answers": [
         "repaired.",
         "reconditioned.",
         "cleaned.",
         "replaced."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "replaced."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "The Clean Air Act:",
      "answers": [
         "sets a schedule for the phase out of CFC/HCFC production.",
         "prohibits venting of refrigerants.",
         "authorizes the EPA to set standards for recovery of refrigerants.",
         "all of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "all of the above"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Measuring the system's final vacuum is always done with:",
      "answers": [
         "the gas ballast wide open.",
         "the vacuum pump operating.",
         "the system being heated.",
         "the system isolated and the vacuum pump off."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "the system isolated and the vacuum pump off."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "A refillable refrigerant cylinder must never be filled to more than ________ of its capacity by weight:",
      "answers": [
         "70%",
         "80%",
         "90%",
         "95%"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "80%"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Of the refrigerants listed below, which refrigerant type have the highest ozone depletion potential?",
      "answers": [
         "HCFCs",
         "HFCs",
         "CFCs",
         "All are equal."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "CFCs"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "This chemical was found in the upper stratosphere and that indicates that the ozone layer is being destroyed.",
      "answers": [
         "chlorine monoxide",
         "carbon monoxide",
         "carbon dioxide",
         "nitrogen dioxide"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "chlorine monoxide"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "What factor(s) affects the speed of evacuation?",
      "answers": [
         "the size of the equipment being evacuated.",
         "the ambient temperature.",
         "the amount of moisture in the system.",
         "all of the above."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "all of the above."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "HCFC refrigerants contain:",
      "answers": [
         "helium, chlorine, fluorine, carbon.",
         "helium, chlorine, fluorine, calcium.",
         "hydrogen, chlorine, fluorine, carbon.",
         "hydrogen, chlorine, fluorine, calcium."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "hydrogen, chlorine, fluorine, carbon."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "When a system will not hold a vacuum after it has been evacuated, then:",
      "answers": [
         "the system is ready to be charged.",
         "the system has been adequately evacuated.",
         "the system may be leaking.",
         "an expansion valve is clogged."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "the system may be leaking."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "All recovery equipment currently being made is required to have:",
      "answers": [
         "a calibration stamp or label.",
         "an EPA approved certification label.",
         "oil-less reciprocating compressors.",
         "manual triple shut-offs."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "an EPA approved certification label."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "The color code for approved refrigerant recovery cylinders is ____________.",
      "answers": [
         "gray tops and yellow bodies",
         "blue tops and green bodies",
         "yellow tops and gray bodies",
         "green tops and gray bodies"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "yellow tops and gray bodies"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "When can you use a disposable cylinder to recover refrigerant?",
      "answers": [
         "When the system contains the same refrigerant as the cylinder, and the cylinder is less than a year old.",
         "When the system contains less than 2 pounds of refrigerant",
         "Only in an emergency to avoid venting.",
         "never"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "never"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which of the following is a \"high-pressure refrigerant\" under EPA's refrigerant recycling regulations?",
      "answers": [
         "R-11",
         "R-22",
         "R-113",
         "R-123"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "R-22"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "After refrigerant liquid transfer between recovery unit and the system being emptied, you need to avoid trapping:",
      "answers": [
         "oil in the transfer unit receiver.",
         "oil in the refrigeration system's cooler.",
         "liquid refrigerant between service valves.",
         "liquid refrigerant in the recovery receiver."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "liquid refrigerant between service valves."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "You can determine safe pressure for leak testing a system from the:",
      "answers": [
         "low-side test-pressure data-plate value.",
         "discharge operating pressure.",
         "ambient +30 degree temperature/pressure value",
         "ambient at standby condition."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "low-side test-pressure data-plate value."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "If a technician has a system where some R-502 was added to an R-22 system. The technician should:",
      "answers": [
         "vent all the refrigerant.",
         "recycle all the refrigerant.",
         "recover all the refrigerant into a separate tank.",
         "recover and reuse all the refrigerant in another system."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "recover all the refrigerant into a separate tank."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Ozone in the stratosphere above the earth consists of:",
      "answers": [
         "molecules of 1 oxygen atom.",
         "molecules of 2 oxygen atoms.",
         "molecules of 3 oxygen atoms.",
         "molecules of 4 oxygen atoms."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "molecules of 3 oxygen atoms."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "The size (capacity) of the vacuum pump and the size of the suction line used will determine:",
      "answers": [
         "where the vacuum hose is connected to the system.",
         "the length of dehydration time.",
         "the type of refrigerant that should be used.",
         "the viscosity of the oil that should be used."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "the length of dehydration time."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "According to the EPA, when dealing with customer complaints regarding additional costs due to refrigerant recovery efforts, the technician should:",
      "answers": [
         "explain that refrigerant recovery is necessary to protect human health and the environment.",
         "explain that refrigerant recovery is required by Federal (and in some cases state and local)laws.",
         "inform the customer that professional service personnel are duty bound to follow the law and to protect the environment.",
         "all of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "all of the above"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "State and local governments can make state laws that:",
      "answers": [
         "follow the Clean Air Act/EPA regulations.",
         "contain stricter regulations than the Clean Air Act/EPA regulations.",
         "Ease or reduce the federal Clean Air Act/EPA regulations.",
         "both A and B"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "both A and B"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "If an oil is hygroscopic it means that it:",
      "answers": [
         "is a good lubricant.",
         "is unrefined mineral oil.",
         "readily absorbs moisture.",
         "can be left open to the ambient air without picking up moisture."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "readily absorbs moisture."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "When dehydrating a system, the system can be heated to:",
      "answers": [
         "avoid oxidation.",
         "increase the oil's viscosity.",
         "decrease the dehydration time.",
         "increase the dehydration time."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "decrease the dehydration time."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "The synthetic lubricant presently used with ternary blends containing HCFCs is:",
      "answers": [
         "alkylbenzene.",
         "mineral oil.",
         "esters.",
         "natural oil."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "alkylbenzene."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Ozone depletion in the stratosphere is what type of problem?",
      "answers": [
         "American",
         "Third World",
         "National",
         "Global"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "Global"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "On a typical three port (three hose) manifold gauge, the center port is used for:",
      "answers": [
         "obtaining gauge readings.",
         "pumping air into system.",
         "recovery, evacuation and charging.",
         "by-pass from low to high side."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "recovery, evacuation and charging."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Ester based oils can be mixed with:",
      "answers": [
         "no other oils.",
         "paraffinic mineral oils only.",
         "alkylbenzene oils only.",
         "mineral oils."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "no other oils."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "CFCs will no longer be manufactured or imported into the United States after:",
      "answers": [
         "1994",
         "1995",
         "1996",
         "1997"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "1995"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which type of refrigerants are chlorine-free?",
      "answers": [
         "HFC's",
         "CFC's",
         "HCFC's",
         "Both HCFCs and CFCs"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "HFC's"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Refrigerant recovery during low ambient temperatures will:",
      "answers": [
         "shorten recovery time, since the recovery tank is cold.",
         "slow the recovery process.",
         "minimize harmful emissions.",
         "require more frequent drier changes."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "slow the recovery process."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "________ is the process of removing refrigerant in any condition from a system and storing it in an external container without necessarily testing or processing it in any way.",
      "answers": [
         "recycling",
         "recovering",
         "reclaiming",
         "restoring"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "recovering"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Containers designated \"refillable\" by DOT are used for transporting recovered pressurized refrigerant _________.",
      "answers": [
         "so refrigerants can be mixed",
         "to meet safety requirements",
         "to prevent overfilling",
         "none of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "to meet safety requirements"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which refrigerant is an HCFC?",
      "answers": [
         "R-123",
         "R-134a",
         "R-410A",
         "R-12"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "R-123"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which refrigerant is an HCFC?",
      "answers": [
         "R-22",
         "R-134a",
         "R-410A",
         "R-12"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "R-22"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "An example of an HFC refrigerant is:",
      "answers": [
         "R-410A.",
         "R-115.",
         "R-22.",
         "R-11."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "R-410A."
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which refrigerant contains a CFC?",
      "answers": [
         "R-12",
         "R-22",
         "R-134a",
         "R-410A"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "R-12"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "An example of a HFC refrigerant is:",
      "answers": [
         "R-134a",
         "R-123",
         "R-22",
         "R-12"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "R-134a"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Which type of refrigerant is the most harmful to stratospheric ozone?",
      "answers": [
         "CFC",
         "HCFC",
         "HFC",
         "Ammonia"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "CFC"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "Of the refrigerants listed below, which has the lowest ozone depletion potential?",
      "answers": [
         "R-22",
         "R-123",
         "R-134a",
         "R-502"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "R-134a"
   },
   {
      "type": "CORE",
      "question": "When evacuating a system, the hoses should be:",
      "answers": [
         "as short in length and as large in diameter as possible.",
         "suitably sized to connect to a gauge manifold.",
         "coiled and taped together.",
         "colored red or blue to meet codes."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "as short in length and as large in diameter as possible."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "What is the maximum allowable factory charge of refrigerant for Type I appliances using CFCs, HCFCs, or HFCs?",
      "answers": [
         "3 pounds",
         "5 pounds",
         "10 pounds",
         "15 pounds"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "5 pounds"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Which of the following are included in EPA's definition of a \"small appliance?\"",
      "answers": [
         "Products manufactured, fully charged and hermetically sealed in a factory.",
         "Products having 15 pounds or less of refrigerant.",
         "Products with compressors under 1 horsepower.",
         "Fully charged components ready for installation in a split system."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "Products manufactured, fully charged and hermetically sealed in a factory."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "When using a self-contained recovery device on a CFC, HCFC, or HFC system with an operating compressor, technicians must:",
      "answers": [
         "recover the refrigerant to 5 inches of mercury vacuum.",
         "recover 80% of the nameplate charge",
         "recover the refrigerant to both 4 inches of mercury vacuum and 80% of the nameplate charge.",
         "either recover the refrigerant to 4 inches of mercury vacuum or 90% of the nameplate charge."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "either recover the refrigerant to 4 inches of mercury vacuum or 90% of the nameplate charge."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Which refrigerants can be mixed in an appliance?",
      "answers": [
         "R-22 and R-407C",
         "R-12 and R-134a",
         "R-407C and R-410A",
         "Refrigerants cannot be mixed"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "Refrigerants cannot be mixed"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "A passive system-dependent recovery process for small appliances",
      "answers": [
         "still uses a pump to recover refrigerant.",
         "must use pressure relief device when recovering refrigerant.",
         "captures refrigerant in a non-pressurized container.",
         "can only be performed on a system with an operating compressor."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "captures refrigerant in a non-pressurized container."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "What may be done to speed the recovery process and ensure that all CFC, HCFC, or HFC refrigerant has been removed from a frost-free refrigerator?",
      "answers": [
         "Cool the compressor to force liquid out of the high side.",
         "Heat the recovery cylinder to vaporize liquid refrigerant.",
         "Turn on the defrost heater to increase the refrigerant's temperature and vaporize any liquid.",
         "Pack ice around the evaporator to ensure maximum liquid is available."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "Turn on the defrost heater to increase the refrigerant's temperature and vaporize any liquid."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "If a reclamation facility receives a tank of mixed refrigerant, they may:",
      "answers": [
         "refuse to accept the refrigerant or charge extra for processing it.",
         "vent the refrigerant.",
         "resell the refrigerant for reuse in its current state.",
         "agree to separate the refrigerants, by the fracking process."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "refuse to accept the refrigerant or charge extra for processing it."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Why should low and high side access valves be installed when recovering refrigerant from a household refrigerator?",
      "answers": [
         "To improve speed of recovery.",
         "To prevent non-condensables contamination.",
         "To protect the recovery machine.",
         "To prevent oil migration."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "To improve speed of recovery."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "All appliances must be equipped with a service aperture or process stub which is used when adding or removing refrigerant from the appliance. What is typically used on small appliances?",
      "answers": [
         "A straight piece of tubing that is entered using a piercing access valve.",
         "A line located 15 inches below the compressor.",
         "A valve installed at the factory which has a 1/4 inch diameter and machine threads.",
         "A service aperture or process stub is not present because small appliances are exempt from this requirement."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "A straight piece of tubing that is entered using a piercing access valve."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "What is the maximum normal charge of HCFC or HFC refrigerant in an appliance that is allowed to use system dependent recovery equipment?",
      "answers": [
         "5 pounds",
         "10 pounds",
         "15 pounds",
         "50 pounds"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "15 pounds"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "How many access valves are needed to recover the refrigerant on a sealed system with an operating compressor that has a completely restricted capillary tube?",
      "answers": [
         "Two valves, one on the high and one on the low side of the system.",
         "Only one access valve, on the low side of the system.",
         "Only one access valve, on the high side of the system.",
         "Two valves, one at the inlet to the compressor and one at the outlet of the condenser coil."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "Only one access valve, on the high side of the system."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "For which of the following refrigeration systems/appliances would it be permissible to use a passive recovery device for recovery of CFCs, HCFCs, and HFCs?",
      "answers": [
         "A centrifugal air conditioner",
         "A reciprocating liquid chiller",
         "A single compressor, large commercial walk-in freezer",
         "A domestic refrigerator"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "A domestic refrigerator"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Which of the following is an approved refrigerant for new household refrigerators, freezers, and combination refrigeration/freezers?",
      "answers": [
         "R-600a",
         "R-1234yf",
         "R-1234zd",
         "R-170"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "R-600a"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Which hydrocarbon refrigerant is approved for retrofit into existing household refrigerators?",
      "answers": [
         "HC R-600a 2 ounces or less",
         "Blended HC R-441A",
         "HC R-290 1 lb. or less",
         "Hydrocarbons are not approved for retrofit applications"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "Hydrocarbons are not approved for retrofit applications"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "When is it essential to take measures to help release trapped CFC, HCFC, or HFC refrigerant from the compressor oil during refrigerant recovery?",
      "answers": [
         "When using self-contained recovery devices.",
         "When using system-dependent active recovery devices.",
         "When using passive recovery devices on small appliances with non-operating compressors.",
         "When the refrigerant system has a low side leak."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "When using passive recovery devices on small appliances with non-operating compressors."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "When installing any type of access fitting onto a sealed system",
      "answers": [
         "the fitting should be leak tested before proceeding with recovery.",
         "it is not necessary to leak test an access fitting.",
         "the fitting need not be leak tested until the total repair is completed.",
         "the system must be pressurized with oxygen-free dry nitrogen before leak testing can be attempted."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "the fitting should be leak tested before proceeding with recovery."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "If, after installing a fitting for the purpose of recovering the appliance's refrigerant, you find that the system pressure is 0 psig;",
      "answers": [
         "Utilize recovery equipment to achieve a 4-inch vacuum.",
         "Pressurize the system with nitrogen prior to recovery.",
         "Refrigerant recovery is not required.",
         "Pressurize the system and leak test."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "Refrigerant recovery is not required."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "System-dependent recovery methods may only be used on appliances containing;",
      "answers": [
         "The refrigerant vapor that is vented off the top of the cylinder must be recovered.",
         "18 pounds of refrigerant or less.",
         "15 pounds of refrigerant or less.",
         "More than 15 pounds of refrigerant."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "15 pounds of refrigerant or less."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "When filling a charging cylinder with a regulated refrigerant;",
      "answers": [
         "The refrigerant vapor that is vented off the top of the cylinder must be recovered.",
         "The refrigerant must be added to the cylinder in the vapor phase to reduce losses.",
         "The refrigerant being added to the cylinder must be weighed in to ensure accuracy.",
         "The refrigerant vapor can be vented off the top of the cylinder as a de minimis release."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "The refrigerant vapor that is vented off the top of the cylinder must be recovered."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Which of the following is an example of a non-condensable?",
      "answers": [
         "Moisture",
         "Air",
         "R-12",
         "R-134a"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Air"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Which of the following is true regarding refrigerant leaks on small appliances?",
      "answers": [
         "EPA does not require repair, but leaks should be repaired whenever possible.",
         "All leaks on Type I equipment must be repaired.",
         "Only very large leaks must be repaired.",
         "All systems with an annualized leak rate of 15 percent or greater must be repaired."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "EPA does not require repair, but leaks should be repaired whenever possible."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "With a non-operating system compressor, recovery equipment must be capable of recovering;",
      "answers": [
         "90 percent of the refrigerant or achieving 4 inches of vacuum.",
         "90 percent of the refrigerant or achieving 5 inches of vacuum.",
         "80 percent of the refrigerant or achieving 5 inches of vacuum.",
         "80 percent of the refrigerant or achieving 4 inches of vacuum."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "80 percent of the refrigerant or achieving 4 inches of vacuum."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "After the refrigerant has been recovered, which of the following can be used to flush the system?",
      "answers": [
         "R-22",
         "Compressed air",
         "Nitrogen",
         "Water"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "Nitrogen"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Type I Certification is required for;",
      "answers": [
         "persons handling refrigerant during maintenance, service, or repair of small appliances.",
         "all persons who work in the factory that produces refrigerants.",
         "all persons working at a refrigerant disposal site.",
         "owners of manufacturing companies that produce CFCs."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "persons handling refrigerant during maintenance, service, or repair of small appliances."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Which HC refrigerant is allowed for use in NEW Domestic Small Appliances?",
      "answers": [
         "R-404A",
         "R-410A",
         "R-600a",
         "R-717"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "R-600a"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "When using a system-dependent recovery system on an appliance that has a non-operating compressor, the technician should;",
      "answers": [
         "Place access fitting on both the low and high side of the system.",
         "Not heat the oil to release refrigerant.",
         "Send the unit to the junkyard to be crushed.",
         "Cut the unit's suction line to release the refrigerant."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "Place access fitting on both the low and high side of the system."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "When using a system-dependent recovery system on an appliance that has an operating compressor, the technician should;",
      "answers": [
         "Run the compressor and recover from the low side of the system only.",
         "Install access fittings on both the high and low-pressure sides of the system.",
         "Run the compressor and recover from the high side of the system only.",
         "Never allow the refrigerant to go to the high side of the system."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "Run the compressor and recover from the high side of the system only."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "On a system with an operating compressor, recovery equipment must be capable of recovering;",
      "answers": [
         "95% of the refrigerant or achieving 5 inches of vacuum.",
         "90% refrigerant or achieving 4 inches of vacuum.",
         "80% refrigerant or achieving 4 inches of vacuum.",
         "100% refrigerant or achieving 0 inches of vacuum."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "90% refrigerant or achieving 4 inches of vacuum."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Small appliances in recreational vehicles may use refrigerants such as Ammonia, Hydrogen, and water. These refrigerants;",
      "answers": [
         "Must be recovered.",
         "Should not be recovered.",
         "Should be stored for later use.",
         "Must be pressurized prior to use."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Should not be recovered."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Recovery equipment must be;",
      "answers": [
         "CSA approved.",
         "Certified by an EPA-approved testing laboratory.",
         "Used on all equipment manufactured after July 1, 1995.",
         "Used on all equipment manufactured after November 15, 1995."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Certified by an EPA-approved testing laboratory."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "When pressurizing a system with nitrogen you should;",
      "answers": [
         "never exceed 3.5 times the high side pressure rating.",
         "charge through a pressure regulator.",
         "install a relief valve in the line downstream from the pressure regulator.",
         "Both B and C."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "Both B and C."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "A small appliance is defined by EPA as;",
      "answers": [
         "Appliances charged, and hermetically sealed in a factory that contain 8 lbs. or less of refrigerant.",
         "Appliances charged, and hermetically sealed in a factory that contain 10 lbs. or less of refrigerant.",
         "Appliances with internal volumes no greater than 3 cubic feet.",
         "Appliances manufactured, charged, and hermetically sealed in a factory that contain 5 lbs. or less of refrigerant."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "Appliances manufactured, charged, and hermetically sealed in a factory that contain 5 lbs. or less of refrigerant."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Applying heat, with a heat gun, to the compressor;",
      "answers": [
         "can help free-up a bound compressor motor.",
         "can help vaporize any trapped liquid refrigerant during recovery.",
         "can help remove trapped refrigerant vapor during recovery.",
         "can aid in isolating and pinpointing a refrigerant leak."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "can help vaporize any trapped liquid refrigerant during recovery."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Self-contained or active recovery equipment;",
      "answers": [
         "Depends on a special charcoal bag filter.",
         "Has its own means to recover refrigerant.",
         "Is not capable of reaching the required liquid rates.",
         "Requires a vacuum pump rated at more than 3 CFM."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Has its own means to recover refrigerant."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Technicians who perform sealed-system service on small appliances must have;",
      "answers": [
         "Type I, II, or III certification.",
         "Type I or Universal certification.",
         "Type II certification.",
         "A Universal 609 certification"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Type I or Universal certification."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Small appliances are equipped with a straight piece of tubing (process stub) that is used;",
      "answers": [
         "As the installation location for a piercing-type access valve.",
         "To help the technician measure system subcooling.",
         "As a p-trap to help capture system contaminants and debris.",
         "To help the technician measure evaporator superheat."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "As the installation location for a piercing-type access valve."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "If regulations change after the technician becomes certified;",
      "answers": [
         "The technician must retake the certification exam.",
         "An additional fee must be paid to the EPA by the technician.",
         "The technician is responsible for complying with any changes to the regulations.",
         "There are no additional compliance requirements for the technician."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "The technician is responsible for complying with any changes to the regulations."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Recovering multiple types of refrigerants in the same cylinder;",
      "answers": [
         "Is an acceptable field service practice.",
         "will make the reclaimed refrigerants unreclaimable.",
         "will require venting to properly dispose of it.",
         "will lower the pressure in the recovery cylinder."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "will make the reclaimed refrigerants unreclaimable."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "If a strong odor is detected while performing a refrigerant recovery process,",
      "answers": [
         "The condenser has been operating incorrectly.",
         "A compressor burnout has likely occurred.",
         "The wrong oil has probably been installed in the unit.",
         "The system has likely been subjected to a power surge."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "A compressor burnout has likely occurred."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "System-dependent or passive recovery equipment;",
      "answers": [
         "Captures refrigerant into a non-pressurized container.",
         "Captures refrigerant into one-trip refrigerant cylinders.",
         "Always requires the assistance of a vacuum pump.",
         "Is always equipped with an external compressor."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "Captures refrigerant into a non-pressurized container."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "When a system is in deep vacuum;",
      "answers": [
         "Never add refrigerant to the system.",
         "Never use a micron gauge.",
         "Never energize the compressor.",
         "Never energize system fans and blowers."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "Never energize the compressor."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "If the EPA regulations should change after a technician becomes certified:",
      "answers": [
         "the technician certification is grandfathered for six months to allow time for taking the recertification exam.",
         "a new certification test must be taken within 90 days to be recertified.",
         "a new certification test must be taken within 90 days to be recertified.",
         "it is the technician's responsibility to comply with any future changes in the law."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "it is the technician's responsibility to comply with any future changes in the law."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "At high temperatures, (i.e., open flames, glowing metal surfaces, etc.) R-12 and R-22 can decompose to form:",
      "answers": [
         "hydrozine gas.",
         "helium gas.",
         "phosgene gas.",
         "all of the above will be formed."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "phosgene gas."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Which of the following refrigerants is most commonly used as a replacement for R-12 in new household refrigerators?",
      "answers": [
         "R-123",
         "R-24",
         "R-141a/141b blend",
         "R-134a"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "R-134a"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Recovery equipment used for the service or repair of small appliances must be certified by an EPA- approved laboratory if the recovery equipment was manufactured after:",
      "answers": [
         "May 15, 1993.",
         "June 15, 1992.",
         "July 15, 1993.",
         "November 15, 1993."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "November 15, 1993."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "What is the maximum allowable factory charge of refrigerant for Type I appliances?",
      "answers": [
         "4 pounds",
         "5 pounds",
         "7 pounds",
         "10 pounds"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "5 pounds"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Why is it important to obtain an accurate pressure reading of refrigerant inside a recovery cylinder?",
      "answers": [
         "The pressure reading along with a temperature reading can indicate if there is excessive air or other non-condensables in the cylinder.",
         "The pressure reading can indicate the remaining cylinder capacity.",
         "The pressure reading can indicate if the refrigerant has been damaged.",
         "both \"a\" and \"c\"."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "The pressure reading along with a temperature reading can indicate if there is excessive air or other non-condensables in the cylinder."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Recovery devices that were manufactured after November 15, 1993 and are used for recovery of refrigerant from small appliances must be capable of:",
      "answers": [
         "recovering 90% of the refrigerant when the compressor is operating or achieving a 4 inch vacuum under the conditions of ARI 740-1993.",
         "recovering 80% of the refrigerant when the compressor is operating.",
         "recovering 95% of the refrigerant when the compressor is operating or achieving a 4 inch vacuum under the conditions of ARI 740-1993.",
         "recovering 85% of the refrigerant when the compressor is operating."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "recovering 90% of the refrigerant when the compressor is operating or achieving a 4 inch vacuum under the conditions of ARI 740-1993."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Solderless piercing valves should not remain installed on refrigeration systems after completion of repairs because:",
      "answers": [
         "they are too expensive to remain on every product.",
         "they tend to leak over time.",
         "they become loose and vibrate.",
         "both \"a\" and \"c\""
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "they tend to leak over time."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "When ever nitrogen is used to pressurize or blow debris out of the system:",
      "answers": [
         "only nitrogen vapor should be used.",
         "only liquid nitrogen should be used.",
         "either liquid or vapor nitrogen can be used.",
         "nitrogen can only be used if mixed with R-22."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "only nitrogen vapor should be used."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "What can cause excessive pressure on the high side of an active self-contained recovery device?",
      "answers": [
         "a closed recovery tank inlet valve.",
         "excessive air or other non-condensables in the recovery tank.",
         "a closed recovery tank outlet valve.",
         "Either choice \"A\" or \"B\""
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "Either choice \"A\" or \"B\""
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Portable refillable tanks or containers used to ship recovered refrigerants must meet what standard(s)?",
      "answers": [
         "Department of Transportation",
         "Community Right-To-Know Act",
         "Underwriters Laboratories",
         "all of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "Department of Transportation"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "A recovery cylinder which is half full of recovered R-22 at normal room temperature (about 75F), in the absence of non-condensables, will be pressurized to:",
      "answers": [
         "250 psig.",
         "200 psig.",
         "175 psig.",
         "130 psig."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "130 psig."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Before beginning a refrigerant recovery procedure it is ALWAYS necessary to:",
      "answers": [
         "allow the system to stabilize.",
         "determine the type of refrigerant in the system.",
         "move the system to an outdoor location.",
         "disconnect the appliance from its power source."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "determine the type of refrigerant in the system."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Which of the following refrigerants must be recovered with equipment currently regulated by the equipment certification requirements of the EPA under Section 608?",
      "answers": [
         "sulfur dioxide",
         "methyl chloride",
         "methyl formate",
         "R-12"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "R-12"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "In the event of a large release of R-12 or R-22 in a contained area, which of the following is true?",
      "answers": [
         "Safety goggles and lined butyl gloves are all that is needed.",
         "Self-contained breathing apparatus (SCUBA) or leaving the area is required.",
         "Respiratory protection is not required, these gases are not toxic.",
         "Dust masks are sufficient protection against harmful vapors."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Self-contained breathing apparatus (SCUBA) or leaving the area is required."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "According to the EPA, which recovery equipment maintenance practice(s) should be performed on a regular basis?",
      "answers": [
         "check recovery device for refrigerant leaks",
         "check vacuum pump for any leaks",
         "check amperage draw of recovery device",
         "all of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "check recovery device for refrigerant leaks"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Small amounts of refrigerant have no odor, therefore if a pungent odor is detected during a system recovery and/or repair:",
      "answers": [
         "it is the characteristic smell of the oil.",
         "the refrigerant should not be recovered.",
         "a compressor burnout has likely occurred.",
         "none of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "a compressor burnout has likely occurred."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "When recovering refrigerant into a non-pressurized container from a refrigerator with an inoperative compressor:",
      "answers": [
         "it is only necessary to recover as much refrigerant as will naturally flow out of the system.",
         "it is not necessary to recover any refrigerant since the refrigerant is probably contaminated.",
         "it is necessary to drive any refrigerant from the oil by using pressurized dry nitrogen.",
         "it is necessary to heat and strike the compressor with a rubber mallet."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "it is necessary to heat and strike the compressor with a rubber mallet."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Large spills of refrigerants can cause suffocation because:",
      "answers": [
         "they smell strong and make breathing difficult.",
         "they are lighter than air and cause dizziness.",
         "they sting the nose and cause sneezing.",
         "they are heavier than air and displace oxygen."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "they are heavier than air and displace oxygen."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Which of the following is not a Type I appliance?",
      "answers": [
         "an MVAC-like system that holds three pounds of R- 12",
         "a water cooler that holds 13 ounces of R-12",
         "a food freezer that holds 22 ounces of R-22",
         "a dehumidifier with seven ounces of R-500"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "an MVAC-like system that holds three pounds of R- 12"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "When R-500 is recovered from an appliance, it:",
      "answers": [
         "can be mixed with either R-22 or R-12 during the recovery process, since R-500 is actually a mixture of the two refrigerants.",
         "can be mixed with R-12 but not R-22 during the recovery process.",
         "need not be recovered since R-500 is not one of the refrigerants covered by the Clean Air Act.",
         "must be recovered into its own recovery vessel (or a recovery cylinder that already contains some R-500)."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "must be recovered into its own recovery vessel (or a recovery cylinder that already contains some R-500)."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "When you connect your service manifold to check system pressures, it's always a good idea to:",
      "answers": [
         "release refrigerant to smell for acid.",
         "use equipment such as hand valves or self-sealing hoses to minimize any release.",
         "recover refrigerant and recharge to specifications, even when no repairs are needed.",
         "use recovery equipment to gain access to the system during testing."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "use equipment such as hand valves or self-sealing hoses to minimize any release."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "The EPA requires that all appliances must be equipped with a service aperture or other device that is used when adding or removing refrigerant from the appliance. For small appliances, this service port typically is:",
      "answers": [
         "a straight piece of tubing, called a Process Tube, that is entered using a piercing access valve.",
         "located 15 inches below the compressor.",
         "installed at the factory, has a 1/4 inch diameter and machine threads.",
         "not present because small appliances are exempt from this requirement."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "a straight piece of tubing, called a Process Tube, that is entered using a piercing access valve."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Anyone who recovers refrigerant during the maintenance, service or repair of small appliances must be certified as either a Universal Technician or a:",
      "answers": [
         "Type I Technician.",
         "Type II Technician.",
         "Type III Technician.",
         "Core certified Technician"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "Type I Technician."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "EPA regulations require the capture of at least 80% of the refrigerant from a small appliance with a non-operating compressor if the technician is using:",
      "answers": [
         "a system-dependent (passive) recovery unit.",
         "a self-contained (active) recovery unit.",
         "either type of recovery unit.",
         "Refrigerant recovery from inoperable systems is not required."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "either type of recovery unit."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "When using a passive system-dependent recovery method on an appliance with an operating compressor, you should run the (appliance's) compressor:",
      "answers": [
         "on 240 volts while recovering the refrigerant from the capillary tube.",
         "for several minutes, shutting it off and then recovering the refrigerant from the high side.",
         "and recover the refrigerant from the high side.",
         "for several minutes, shutting it off and then recovering the refrigerant from the low side."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "and recover the refrigerant from the high side."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "A passive system-dependent recovery device for small appliances:",
      "answers": [
         "never needs the use of a pump, compressor or heat to recover the refrigerant.",
         "must use a pressure relief device when recovering refrigerant.",
         "captures refrigerant in a non-pressurized container.",
         "can only be performed on a system with an operating compressor."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "captures refrigerant in a non-pressurized container."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "The sale of CFC and HCFC refrigerants is:",
      "answers": [
         "banned.",
         "limited by law to equipment owners of commercial equipment.",
         "allowed only if the quantity is less than 5 pounds.",
         "restricted to technicians who are EPA certified in refrigerant recovery."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "restricted to technicians who are EPA certified in refrigerant recovery."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Which of the refrigerants listed below should be recovered with current EPA-approved recovery devices?",
      "answers": [
         "ammonia",
         "hydrogen",
         "water",
         "none of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "none of the above"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "When servicing a small appliance with a leak:",
      "answers": [
         "it is mandatory to repair the leak within 30 days.",
         "it is mandatory to repair the leak if more than 35% of the charge escapes within a 12 month period.",
         "it is not mandatory to repair the leak but do so whenever",
         "Both \"a\" and \"b\""
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "it is not mandatory to repair the leak but do so whenever"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "For which of the following refrigeration systems/appliances would it be permissible to use a passive recovery device for refrigerant recovery?",
      "answers": [
         "a centrifugal air conditioner",
         "a reciprocating liquid chiller",
         "a single compressor, large commercial walk-in freezer",
         "a domestic refrigerator"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "a domestic refrigerator"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "When using any equipment or servicing any system that has schrader valves, it is \"critical\" to:",
      "answers": [
         "inspect the schrader valve core for bends and breakage.",
         "replace any damaged schrader valve core to prevent leakage.",
         "cap the schrader ports to prevent accidental depression of the valve core.",
         "all of the above."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "all of the above."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "If R-12 or R-22 are exposed to high temperatures, (from open flames or glowing hot metal surfaces for example), these refrigerants can decompose to form:",
      "answers": [
         "hydrochloric and hydrofluoric acids.",
         "sulfuric and phosphoric acids.",
         "boric and chromic acids.",
         "none of the above."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "hydrochloric and hydrofluoric acids."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "When using a graduated charging cylinder, any refrigerant that is vented from the charging cylinder:",
      "answers": [
         "does not need to be recovered.",
         "must be recovered.",
         "Is considered a de minimis release.",
         "None of the above."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "must be recovered."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "A standard vacuum pump designed specifically for evacuation and dehydration can:",
      "answers": [
         "be used alone as a self-contained (active) recovery device.",
         "never be used as a recovery device in combination with a pressurized container.",
         "be used alone as a substitute for any recovery device.",
         "be used alone as a system-dependent (passive) recovery device."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "never be used as a recovery device in combination with a pressurized container."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "The EPA Section 608 certification must be renewed every:",
      "answers": [
         "2 years.",
         "3 years.",
         "10 years.",
         "The EPA certification has no expiration date."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "The EPA certification has no expiration date."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Prior to shipping any used refrigerant it is necessary to:",
      "answers": [
         "properly label the refrigerant container.",
         "properly complete shipping paperwork.",
         "check that the refrigerant container meets Department of Transportation standards.",
         "all of the above."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "all of the above."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "A refrigerant that can be used as a direct service \"drop-in\" substitute for R-12 in a small appliance is:",
      "answers": [
         "R-410A.",
         "R-134a.",
         "R-141b.",
         "none of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "none of the above"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "After installing and opening a piercing access valve, if the system pressure is _______ do not begin the recovery procedure.",
      "answers": [
         "0 psig",
         "15 psig",
         "30 psig",
         "40 psig"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "0 psig"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "The EPA definition of a small appliance includes which of the following?",
      "answers": [
         "a device manufactured, charged and hermetically sealed in a factory",
         "a device with a charge of 5 pounds or less",
         "products with compressors under a quarter horsepower",
         "Both \"a\" and \"b\""
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "Both \"a\" and \"b\""
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "When using _________, it is essential to take extra measures (such as heating or striking the compressor), to help release trapped refrigerant from the compressor oil.",
      "answers": [
         "an active self-contained recovery device",
         "passive system-dependent recovery devices on an operating system",
         "passive system-dependent recovery devices on a small appliances with a non-operating compressor.",
         "when the refrigerant system has a low side leak"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "passive system-dependent recovery devices on a small appliances with a non-operating compressor."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "It is an EPA regulation that any person who opens an appliance for maintenance, service or repair must have at least one self-contained recovery machine available at their place of business. The only exception to this rule are persons working on:",
      "answers": [
         "small appliances.",
         "low pressure appliances.",
         "high pressure appliances.",
         "R-410A systems."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "small appliances."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Which of the following are part of the EPA's recommended safe work practices?",
      "answers": [
         "wear safety glasses or goggles when working with any compressed gases",
         "wear a respirator when working with any refrigerant",
         "wear butyl-lined gloves when connecting/disconnecting hoses",
         "both \"a\" and \"c\""
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "both \"a\" and \"c\""
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Recovery devices that were manufactured before November 15, 1993 and are used for recovery of refrigerant from small appliances must be capable of:",
      "answers": [
         "recovering 80% of the refrigerant whether or not the compressor is operating or achieving a 4 inch vacuum under conditions of ARI 740-1993",
         "recovering 70% of the refrigerant if the compressor is operating or achieving a 4 inch vacuum under conditions of ARI 740-1993",
         "achieving a 10 inch vacuum under conditions of ARI 740-1993",
         "of recovering all the refrigerant if they are still to be used."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "recovering 80% of the refrigerant whether or not the compressor is operating or achieving a 4 inch vacuum under conditions of ARI 740-1993"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Piercing-type valves should only be used on which of the following tubing materials?",
      "answers": [
         "copper",
         "aluminum",
         "steel",
         "both \"a\" and \"b\""
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "both \"a\" and \"b\""
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "When using a passive system-dependent recovery process, you should access both the high and low side of the system for the refrigerant recovery if _____________ .",
      "answers": [
         "there is a leak in the system",
         "the system's compressor operates normally",
         "the system's compressor only runs at half speed",
         "the system's compressor does not run"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "the system's compressor does not run"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "On a small appliance with an operating compressor that has a completely plugged capillary tube, what is the minimum number of access valves that are needed to evacuate the refrigerant?",
      "answers": [
         "Only one access valve, on the low side of the system.",
         "Only one access valve, on the high of the system.",
         "Two valves, one on the high and one on the low side of the system because the cap tube is plugged.",
         "all of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Only one access valve, on the high of the system."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Technicians with a Type I small appliance certification are certified to recover refrigerant during the maintenance, service or repair of:",
      "answers": [
         "small unitary air-conditioning systems with 7 pounds or less of refrigerant.",
         "packaged terminal air conditioners (\"PTACs\") with 5 pounds or less of refrigerant.",
         "low pressure equipment.",
         "motor vehicle air-conditioning equipment."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "packaged terminal air conditioners (\"PTACs\") with 5 pounds or less of refrigerant."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "A recovery cylinder which is half full of recovered R-500 at normal room temperature (about 75F), in the absence of non-condensables, will be pressurized to:",
      "answers": [
         "30 psig.",
         "75 psig.",
         "95 psig.",
         "120 psig."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "95 psig."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "A Very-High-Pressure appliance is one that uses a refrigerant with a liquid phase saturation pressure above 355 psia at 104F. This definition includes but is not limited to appliances using which of the refrigerants listed below:",
      "answers": [
         "R-23.",
         "R-13.",
         "R-503.",
         "all of the above."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "all of the above."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "A refrigerant that can be used as a direct service \"drop-in\" substitute for R-22 in a small appliance is:",
      "answers": [
         "R-410A.",
         "R-134a.",
         "R-141b.",
         "none of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "none of the above"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "If a large leak of refrigerant occurs in an enclosed area and no self-contained breathing apparatus is available, then the technician should:",
      "answers": [
         "Put on a dust mask and butyl lined gloves, then try to stop the leak.",
         "Put on a dust mask, use a leak detector to locate the leak and try to stop the leak.",
         "Vacate and ventilate the spill area.",
         "all of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "Vacate and ventilate the spill area."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "When recovering refrigerant from a household refrigerator who's compressor does not run, it is recommended that low and high side access valves be installed because____________.",
      "answers": [
         "it can enhance the speed of recovery.",
         "it may be necessary to achieve required recovery efficiency.",
         "otherwise, the refrigerator's compressor may be damaged",
         "both \"a\" and \"b\""
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "both \"a\" and \"b\""
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "A recovery cylinder which is half full of recovered R-12 at normal room temperature (about 75F), in the absence of non-condensables, will be pressurized to:",
      "answers": [
         "30 psig.",
         "75 psig.",
         "150 psig.",
         "200 psig."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "75 psig."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "When using nitrogen, the nitrogen tank should always be equipped with a:",
      "answers": [
         "regulator.",
         "level sensor.",
         "yellow top.",
         "hand valve."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "regulator."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "To avoid accidental removal of liquid refrigerant when recovering vapor from a system, using a self- contained (active) recovery device that cannot handle liquid refrigerant, you should draw vapor from the:",
      "answers": [
         "capillary tube.",
         "low side.",
         "high side.",
         "all of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "high side."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "If you install an access fitting onto a sealed system:",
      "answers": [
         "the fitting should be leak tested before proceeding with recovery.",
         "it is not necessary to leak test the access fitting.",
         "the fitting does not need to be leak tested until the total repair is completed.",
         "the system must be pressurized with dry nitrogen before leak testing can be performed."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "the fitting should be leak tested before proceeding with recovery."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "If you are recovering refrigerant from a frost- free refrigerator, you should:",
      "answers": [
         "cool the compressor to force liquid out of the high side.",
         "heat the recovery cylinder to vaporize liquid refrigerant.",
         "turn on the defrost heater to vaporize any trapped liquid.",
         "pack ice around the evaporator to ensure maximum liquid is available."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "turn on the defrost heater to vaporize any trapped liquid."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "When checking for the existence of non-condensable gases inside a recovery cylinder, why is it proper procedure to allow the temperature of the cylinder to stabilize at room temperature before taking a pressure reading",
      "answers": [
         "To prevent safety valves from purging excess refrigerant.",
         "Because it is a quick method of determining refrigerant level inside the tank.",
         "Because a temperature reading alone is enough to determine refrigerant quality.",
         "Because any comparisons to a pressure-temperature chart is only valid if both the pressure and temperature of the refrigerant are stable."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "Because any comparisons to a pressure-temperature chart is only valid if both the pressure and temperature of the refrigerant are stable."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "A standard vacuum pump designed specifically for evacuation and dehydration can:",
      "answers": [
         "be used alone as a self-contained (active) recovery device.",
         "be only used as a recovery device in combination with a non-pressurized container.",
         "be used alone as a substitute for any recovery device.",
         "be used alone as a system-dependent (passive) recovery device."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "be only used as a recovery device in combination with a non-pressurized container."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "When ever nitrogen is used to pressurize or blow debris out of the system, the nitrogen:",
      "answers": [
         "must be recovered.",
         "can be vented.",
         "nitrogen should never be used.",
         "nitrogen can only be used if mixed with R-22."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "can be vented."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "If a reclamation processing plant is given a recovery tank containing a mixture of refrigerants, they can:",
      "answers": [
         "refuse to process the refrigerant and return it.",
         "agree to destroy the refrigerant, but typically a substantial fee is charged for the destruction.",
         "resell the refrigerant for reuse in its current state.",
         "both \"a\" and \"b\""
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "both \"a\" and \"b\""
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Refrigerant recovery devices must be equipped with low loss fittings. Low loss fittings are used to:",
      "answers": [
         "connect the recovery device to an appliance and which are manually closed (or which close automatically) when they are disconnected, to prevent loss of refrigerant from hoses.",
         "connect the recovery device to an appliance and which leak only small amounts of refrigerant during use.",
         "are used to connect the recovery device to an appliance and which must be discarded after each use.",
         "none of the above."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "connect the recovery device to an appliance and which are manually closed (or which close automatically) when they are disconnected, to prevent loss of refrigerant from hoses."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Recovery or recycling equipment which was manufactured after November 15,1993 and is used to recover refrigerant from small appliances prior to disposal of the small appliances must be used to:",
      "answers": [
         "recover 95% or the refrigerant from the appliance whether or not the compressor is functional.",
         "recover 80% of the refrigerant in an appliance if the appliance's compressor is inoperative.",
         "recover 90% of the refrigerant in an appliance if the appliance's compressor is operational",
         "both \"b\" and \"c\""
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "both \"b\" and \"c\""
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "The sale of refrigerants is:",
      "answers": [
         "banned.",
         "limited by law to equipment owners.",
         "allowed only if there is proof of need.",
         "restricted to technicians who are EPA certified in refrigerant recovery."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "restricted to technicians who are EPA certified in refrigerant recovery."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "A recovery cylinder which is half full of recovered R-410A at 90 degrees F, in the absence of non-condensables, will be pressurized to:",
      "answers": [
         "100 psig.",
         "200 psig.",
         "300 psig.",
         "400 psig."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "300 psig."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "Which refrigerants can be mixed?",
      "answers": [
         "R-12 and R-134a",
         "R-12 and R-500",
         "R-22 and R-410A",
         "refrigerants can never be mixed"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "refrigerants can never be mixed"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type I",
      "question": "When transporting refrigerants, DOT (Department of Transportation) Regulation number 49 CFR requires ______________ to be recorded on the shipping papers for hazard class 2.2, Non Flammable Compressed Gases?",
      "answers": [
         "volume of each cylinder",
         "total cubic feet of each refrigerant",
         "number of cylinders of each gas",
         "total weight of all cylinders"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "number of cylinders of each gas"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Which of the following always falls under the EPA definition for \"major maintenance, service, or repair?\"",
      "answers": [
         "Replacing an oil filter",
         "Replacing an expansion valve",
         "Replacing a compressor",
         "Replacing an accumulator"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "Replacing a compressor"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Recovering refrigerant from a system in the vapor phase will minimize the loss of which of the following?",
      "answers": [
         "water",
         "oil",
         "refrigerant",
         "non-condensables"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "oil"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "After system servicing, and recharging, why is refrigerant vapor reintroduced to the chiller before refrigerant liquid?",
      "answers": [
         "Vapor charging increases pressure slowly, preventing failure of the rupture disk.",
         "Vapor charging is faster than liquid charging.",
         "Liquid charging is more difficult to control than vapor charging.",
         "Liquid charged into a deep vacuum will evaporate and may lower the temperature freezing water in the heat exchanger tube bundle."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "Liquid charged into a deep vacuum will evaporate and may lower the temperature freezing water in the heat exchanger tube bundle."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "In the event of a large release of CFC, HCFC, or HFC refrigerant in a contained area which of the following is true?",
      "answers": [
         "Safety goggles and lined butyl gloves are sufficient.",
         "Self-contained breathing apparatus (SCBA) or leaving the area is required.",
         "Respiratory protection is not required.",
         "Dust masks are sufficient."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Self-contained breathing apparatus (SCBA) or leaving the area is required."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "A comfort-cooling appliance containing 50 pounds or more of R-22 is found to be leaking beyond the applicable leak rate threshold. Unless granted additional time, how many days do you have to repair the leak and conduct the initial leak verification test?",
      "answers": [
         "1 day",
         "10 days",
         "30 days",
         "45 days"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "30 days"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "What are refrigeration and air-conditioning compressor heaters used for?",
      "answers": [
         "To reduce the amount of refrigerant in the oil.",
         "To prevent refrigerant vaporization.",
         "To reduce the amount of entrained water in the receiver.",
         "To prevent acid pitting."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "To reduce the amount of refrigerant in the oil."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "What is a characteristic of a refrigerant oil that is hygroscopic?",
      "answers": [
         "It is a good lubricant.",
         "It is crude oil and unrefined.",
         "It readily absorbs moisture.",
         "It can be left open to ambient air."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "It readily absorbs moisture."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "An appliance normally containing more than 50 pounds of R-22 refrigerant was found to have a 35% annual leak rate. After the repair, how many successful verification tests are required?",
      "answers": [
         "One. Performed before the appliance is recharged.",
         "Two. The first performed before the appliance is recharged, and the second performed after the appliance returns to normal operating conditions.",
         "One. Performed once the appliance returns to normal operating conditions.",
         "Three. The first performed before the appliance is recharged, the second performed after the appliance returns to normal operating conditions, and the third performed three months later."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Two. The first performed before the appliance is recharged, and the second performed after the appliance returns to normal operating conditions."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Which of the following should be replaced if a system is opened for servicing?",
      "answers": [
         "Filter drier",
         "Thermostat",
         "Metering device",
         "Crankcase heater"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "Filter drier"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "What must a system owner do, once the threshold leak rate has been exceeded on any low-pressure system using an ozone depleting refrigerant?",
      "answers": [
         "Retire the appliance the following year.",
         "Repair all of the leaks and submit a report about the repair to the EPA.",
         "Immediately mothball the appliance until it is retrofitted.",
         "Repair the appliance enough to bring the leak rate below the threshold, retrofit, or retire the appliance."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "Repair the appliance enough to bring the leak rate below the threshold, retrofit, or retire the appliance."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "When could a reciprocating compressor be damaged if energized?",
      "answers": [
         "When the discharge service valve is closed.",
         "When the suction service valve is open.",
         "When the discharge service valve is open.",
         "When the demand for cooling is at a steady state."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "When the discharge service valve is closed."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Why could a recycling or recovery machine that uses a hermetic compressor overheat when drawing deep vacuums?",
      "answers": [
         "It runs faster than other equipment with oil less compressors.",
         "The motor relies on the flow of refrigerant through the compressor for cooling.",
         "It has a higher compression ratio limit than other equipment.",
         "The oils used in hermetic compressors are a lower viscosity than the oils used in other equipment."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "The motor relies on the flow of refrigerant through the compressor for cooling."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Recovered refrigerant may contain which of the following impurities?",
      "answers": [
         "Ammonia, carbon dioxide, and methyl chloride",
         "Sodium chloride, potassium nitrate, and silicone oil",
         "Sulphur dioxide and methane",
         "Acids, moisture, and oil"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "Acids, moisture, and oil"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "After installation of a field piped split system, the unit should first be pressurized with:",
      "answers": [
         "air and leak checked.",
         "R-22 and leak checked.",
         "R-410A and leak checked.",
         "nitrogen and leak checked."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "nitrogen and leak checked."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Which of the following is an indicator of a leak in a high-pressure system with a capillary tube?",
      "answers": [
         "High head pressure",
         "Low water temperature",
         "Excessive superheat",
         "Frequent purging"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "Excessive superheat"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Your recovery/recycling machine has R-22 refrigerant in it. You now have to recover refrigerant from an R-410A unit. What must be done before recovery?",
      "answers": [
         "Change the recovery cylinder on the recovery machine.",
         "Change the expansion valve on the recovery machine.",
         "Change the filter and expansion valve on the recovery machine.",
         "Remove the R-22 from the recovery unit and change the filter."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "Remove the R-22 from the recovery unit and change the filter."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Which condition can cause excessive pressure on the high side of a self-contained (active) recovery device?",
      "answers": [
         "When the thermal expansion valve is stuck open.",
         "When the capacity of the recovery tank is larger than the charge size of the system.",
         "When there is a large volume of non-condensable gas in the refrigerant being recovered.",
         "When the system is set for no subcooling."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "When there is a large volume of non-condensable gas in the refrigerant being recovered."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "After refrigerant liquid has been recovered from the appliance, any remaining vapor is.",
      "answers": [
         "purged to the atmosphere.",
         "isolated in the appliance.",
         "pumped into appliance receiver.",
         "removed by the recovery system."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "removed by the recovery system."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "What gas should be used to leak check a system designed for use with R-410A that has been opened for a major system repair?",
      "answers": [
         "Any available HFC",
         "Any available HCFC",
         "Pressurized nitrogen",
         "Compressed air"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "Pressurized nitrogen"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "A customer has an industrial process refrigeration system that contains 1000 lbs. of R-22 that has exceeded the applicable leak rate threshold. How often is the customer required to perform a leak inspection?",
      "answers": [
         "Every month",
         "Every 3 months",
         "Every 6 months",
         "Every 12 months"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Every 3 months"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "When first inspecting a hermetic system known to be leaking, you should look for:",
      "answers": [
         "frost on the tubing.",
         "puddles of refrigerant.",
         "particles of filter drier core.",
         "traces of oil."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "traces of oil."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "A crankcase heater is often used to prevent refrigerant from mixing with compressor oil during periods of:",
      "answers": [
         "Low ambient temperature",
         "High ambient temperature",
         "Low humidity",
         "High humidity"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "Low ambient temperature"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Refrigerant should be recovered from the condenser outlet if the condenser is;",
      "answers": [
         "Below the receiver",
         "Above the receiver",
         "On the roof",
         "Is leaking"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "Below the receiver"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "A new split system should be checked for leaks by;",
      "answers": [
         "pressurizing the system with a few ounces of HCFC-22 and compressed air.",
         "pressurizing the system with a few ounces of CFC-12 and an inert gas.",
         "releasing the factory refrigerant charge in the condensing unit.",
         "pressurizing the system with a few ounces of system refrigerant and an inert gas."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "pressurizing the system with a few ounces of system refrigerant and an inert gas."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "When using a recovery unit on a system containing 100 lbs. of R-410A it must be evacuated to;",
      "answers": [
         "0 inches of Mercury",
         "4 inches of Mercury",
         "10 inches of Mercury",
         "15 inches of Mercury"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "0 inches of Mercury"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "What can be done with a refrigerant trace gas and nitrogen mixture after a system leak is found?",
      "answers": [
         "Recover the mixture.",
         "Recover in a special recovery tank.",
         "Recycle the refrigerant back into the system.",
         "Release to the atmosphere."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "Release to the atmosphere."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "If a leaking appliance with a regulated refrigerant is not going to be repaired, it must be;",
      "answers": [
         "retrofitted or retired within 3 months.",
         "retrofitted or retired within 12 months.",
         "replaced within 3 months.",
         "replaced within 12 months."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "retrofitted or retired within 12 months."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Non-condensables will cause;",
      "answers": [
         "Low superheat",
         "Low discharge pressure",
         "High superheat",
         "High discharge pressure"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "High discharge pressure"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "A comfort cooling system that contains 50 pounds or more of R-410A is leaking. What will be the new maximum allowable annual leak rate starting in 2019?",
      "answers": [
         "5%",
         "10%",
         "15%",
         "20%"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "10%"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Refrigerants CFC-12, HCFC-22, and HFC-134a are all classified as Type _______ substances.",
      "answers": [
         "B-1",
         "B-2",
         "A-1",
         "A-2"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "A-1"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "What must the equipment owners/operators include in recovered refrigerant records for equipment with refrigerant charges that range from 5 to 50 pounds?",
      "answers": [
         "The quantity of refrigerant (by type) added or recovered from disposed appliances each year and quantity of refrigerant (by type) sent for reclamation or destruction.",
         "The quantity of refrigerant (by type) added or recovered from disposed appliances in each calendar month and quantity of refrigerant (by type) sent for reclamation or destruction.",
         "The type of refrigerant, the amount added for seasonal variance, the amount added to a new unit, recovered from disposed appliances in each calendar month and quantity of refrigerant (by type) sent for reclamation or destruction.",
         "The amount of new refrigerant added to a system in each calendar month and quantity of refrigerant (by type) sent for reclamation or destruction."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "The quantity of refrigerant (by type) added or recovered from disposed appliances in each calendar month and quantity of refrigerant (by type) sent for reclamation or destruction."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "When recovering refrigerant from a medium-pressure system with more than 200 lbs. of refrigerant, recover to a level of;",
      "answers": [
         "0\" Hg",
         "4\" Hg",
         "10\" Hg",
         "15\" Hg"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "15\" Hg"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "A high-pressure appliance containing less than 200 lbs. of an HCFC or HFC refrigerant must be evacuated (recovered) to a level of;",
      "answers": [
         "15 inches of vacuum",
         "10 inches of vacuum",
         "4 inches of vacuum",
         "0 inches of vacuum"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "0 inches of vacuum"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "A high-pressure appliance containing 210 lbs. of R-407C refrigerant must be evacuated (recovered) to a level of;",
      "answers": [
         "15 inches of vacuum",
         "10 inches of vacuum",
         "4 inches of vacuum",
         "0 inches of vacuum"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "10 inches of vacuum"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Proper recovery techniques begin with the use of appropriate recovery equipment that has been certified by;",
      "answers": [
         "EPA only",
         "Manufacturers approved by UL",
         "EPA approved laboratory",
         "EPA field supervisors"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "EPA approved laboratory"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "EPA regulations require that all Industrial Process Refrigeration (IPR) systems containing more than 50 pounds of refrigerant MUST be repaired when the annual leak rate exceeds;",
      "answers": [
         "10%",
         "20%",
         "30%",
         "40%"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "30%"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Leaks must be repaired on industrial process and refrigeration units with a 50-pound charge or greater when the annualized leak rate reaches _____ or more.",
      "answers": [
         "10%",
         "20%",
         "30%",
         "40%"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "30%"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "EPA regulations state that removal of which component constitutes a \"major repair\"?",
      "answers": [
         "Pressure switch",
         "Compressor",
         "Liquid line drier",
         "Evaporator fan motor"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Compressor"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "When an appliance containing 50 pounds or more of a regulated refrigerant leaks refrigerant at an annual rate of 125% or more, what must be included on the leak inspections records?",
      "answers": [
         "Initial verification, verification tests and records of recovered refrigerant from equipment.",
         "Quantity of refrigerant sold, procedures performed, date of call, name, address and phone number of manufacturer.",
         "Quantity of refrigerant, address of service technician, number of years in HVAC.",
         "The amount of refrigerant and addresses only."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "Initial verification, verification tests and records of recovered refrigerant from equipment."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "A refrigerant sensor which will sound an alarm and automatically start a ventilation system in occupied equipment rooms falls under ASHRAE Standard;",
      "answers": [
         "15",
         "34",
         "44",
         "60"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "15"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Unless plans are made to replace a system with a leak rate that exceeds the maximum leak rate, repairs must be made within;",
      "answers": [
         "30 days.",
         "45 days.",
         "60 days.",
         "90 days."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "30 days."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Which of the following refrigerants is classified as a very high-pressure refrigerant?",
      "answers": [
         "CFC-11",
         "R-744",
         "HCFC-123",
         "R-410A"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "R-744"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "When dehydrating a system, it should be evacuated to a minimum level of;",
      "answers": [
         "30 inches of Mercury",
         "25,000 Microns",
         "500 Microns",
         "EPA does not have a requirement"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "500 Microns"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "What happens to a refrigerant that is heated above the saturation temperature?",
      "answers": [
         "It remains in the vapor state.",
         "It remains in the liquid state.",
         "It absorbs moisture at an increased rate.",
         "It cools the compressor more efficiently."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "It remains in the vapor state."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "All HVAC/R systems must be protected by a;",
      "answers": [
         "Low-pressure switch",
         "High-pressure switch",
         "Compressor impedance overload",
         "Pressure relief valve"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "Pressure relief valve"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "What conditions allow for a system to be opened and repaired without recovering the refrigerant to the required vacuum level?",
      "answers": [
         "A system with a large leak and internal pressure of 0 psig",
         "A system that is undergoing a major component replacement",
         "A system that uses a CFC refrigerant",
         "A system that has a non-operational compressor"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "A system with a large leak and internal pressure of 0 psig"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Heat Pumps that use R-410A should be leak checked with:",
      "answers": [
         "HFCs.",
         "HCFCs to lower the cost of discarding the refrigerant.",
         "pressurized nitrogen.",
         "compressed oxygen."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "pressurized nitrogen."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Heat Pumps that have been retrofitted from R-22 to R-407C should be leak checked with:",
      "answers": [
         "HFCs.",
         "HCFCs.",
         "pressurized nitrogen.",
         "compressed air."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "pressurized nitrogen."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "To change the compressor on a system containing R-410A, you must isolate the compressor then:",
      "answers": [
         "Simply remove the compressor.",
         "Evacuate the isolated section of the system to atmospheric pressure and hold. if system pressure does not rise, remove the compressor.",
         "Evacuate the isolated section of the system to 10 inches of vacuum and hold. If system pressure does not rise, remove the compressor.",
         "Evacuate the isolated section of the system to 15 inches of vacuum and hold. If system pressure does not rise, remove the compressor."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Evacuate the isolated section of the system to atmospheric pressure and hold. if system pressure does not rise, remove the compressor."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "The method to charge a system that has a normal charge of 80 pounds is to charge with:",
      "answers": [
         "vapor through the suction line service valve.",
         "liquid through the discharge service valve.",
         "liquid through the suction service valve.",
         "liquid through the liquid-line service valve."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "liquid through the liquid-line service valve."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "After installation of a field-piped R-410A split heat pump, the unit should first be:",
      "answers": [
         "evacuated.",
         "pressurized with R-22 then leak checked.",
         "pressurized with R-410A then leak checked.",
         "pressurized with nitrogen then leak checked."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "pressurized with nitrogen then leak checked."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Pressure relief valves must not be:",
      "answers": [
         "installed in series.",
         "installed in parallel.",
         "installed vertically.",
         "installed horizontally."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "installed in series."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "When charging an R-12 refrigeration system that uses a water-cooled condenser, you must first charge with vapor to a pressure of at least _______, before switching to Liquid charging.",
      "answers": [
         "0 psig.",
         "20 psig.",
         "35 psig.",
         "100 psig."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "35 psig."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Your recovery/recycling machine has R-22 refrigerant in it. You now have to recover refrigerant from a unit with R-410A. What must be done before your recovery unit can be used to recovery R-410A?",
      "answers": [
         "The recovery unit must be EPA certified for use with R-410A.",
         "The recovery tank must be designed for the pressure of R-410A.",
         "The filter and lubricant in the recovery unit must be changed, and the recovery unit evacuated",
         "All of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "All of the above"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "After reaching the required recovery vacuum on a system you must:",
      "answers": [
         "immediately disconnect the recycling or recovery equipment and open the system for service.",
         "immediately break the vacuum with nitrogen and open the system for service.",
         "immediately pressurize the system with nitrogen and perform a leak check.",
         "wait to see if the system pressure rises, indicating that there is still refrigerant in liquid form or refrigerant trapped in the oil."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "wait to see if the system pressure rises, indicating that there is still refrigerant in liquid form or refrigerant trapped in the oil."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "In a refrigeration system, the component directly following the evaporator is the:",
      "answers": [
         "receiver.",
         "metering device.",
         "accumulator.",
         "condenser."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "accumulator."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "A reciprocating compressor should not be energized when",
      "answers": [
         "the discharge service valve is closed.",
         "the suction service valve is open.",
         "the discharge service valve is open.",
         "there is a demand for cooling."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "the discharge service valve is closed."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "R-410A requires a high-pressure manifold gauge and hose set. They must have a:",
      "answers": [
         "2000 psig burst pressure and 400 psig working pressure.",
         "2000 psig burst pressure and 800 psig working pressure.",
         "4000 psig burst pressure and 400 psig working pressure.",
         "4000 psig burst pressure and 800 psig working pressure."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "4000 psig burst pressure and 800 psig working pressure."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "The refrigerant pressure inside an R-410A unit which is at room temperature (72F) and not operating is:",
      "answers": [
         "approximately 74 psig.",
         "approximately 110 psig.",
         "approximately 210 psig.",
         "approximately 310 psig."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "approximately 210 psig."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Every air conditioning or refrigerating system should be protected by a:",
      "answers": [
         "pressure relief device.",
         "properly located stop valve.",
         "low pressure control.",
         "refrigerant receiver."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "pressure relief device."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "To change the compressor on a system containing 40 pounds R-500, using a recycling machine that was manufactured AFTER November 15, 1993, you must isolate the compressor then:",
      "answers": [
         "Simply remove the compressor.",
         "Evacuate the isolated section of the system to atmospheric pressure, then remove the compressor.",
         "Evacuate the isolated section of the system to 10 inches of vacuum and hold. If system pressure does not rise, remove the compressor.",
         "Evacuate the isolated section of the system to 15 inches of vacuum and hold. If system pressure does not rise, remove the compressor."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "Evacuate the isolated section of the system to 10 inches of vacuum and hold. If system pressure does not rise, remove the compressor."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "When inspecting a system for leaks, you should look for:",
      "answers": [
         "frost on the pipes.",
         "puddles of liquid refrigerant.",
         "particles from the drier core.",
         "traces of oil."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "traces of oil."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "When a new system has been assembled, the first thing to do is:",
      "answers": [
         "evacuate the system.",
         "pressurize the system with an inert gas and leak check.",
         "pressurize the system with refrigerant to be used in the system.",
         "introduce an initial charge of refrigerant and start the compressor."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "pressurize the system with an inert gas and leak check."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "R-410A is different from other ASHRAE 400 series non- azeotropic blends because:",
      "answers": [
         "R-410A behaves as a near azeotropic refrigerant, and can be topped off.",
         "R-410A is a HCFC.",
         "R-410A uses mineral oil.",
         "All of the above."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "R-410A behaves as a near azeotropic refrigerant, and can be topped off."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Manifold gauge set hoses should have self-sealing connectors or hand valves to:",
      "answers": [
         "minimize the chance of an explosion during use.",
         "prevent venting during recycling.",
         "prevent a vapor lock during rapid liquid transfer.",
         "minimize the release of refrigerant when the hoses are connected and disconnected."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "minimize the release of refrigerant when the hoses are connected and disconnected."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "When using recovery or recycling equipment that was manufactured AFTER November 15, 1993: you must evacuate a system containing MORE than 200 pounds of CFC-12 to _________ before making a major repair:",
      "answers": [
         "0 psig.",
         "4 inches of Hg vacuum.",
         "10 inches of Hg vacuum.",
         "15 inches of Hg vacuum."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "15 inches of Hg vacuum."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "With an air-cooled condenser on the roof of a building and the evaporator on the first floor, recovery should first occur:",
      "answers": [
         "from the vapor line entering the condenser.",
         "from the discharge of the compressor.",
         "from the liquid line entering the evaporator.",
         "on the suction side of the compressor."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "from the liquid line entering the evaporator."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Never use oxygen or compressed air to leak-check hardware because R-410A can:",
      "answers": [
         "explode when mixed with air or oxygen.",
         "fractionate when mixed with oxygen.",
         "condense when exposed to oxygen.",
         "none of the above."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "explode when mixed with air or oxygen."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Dry nitrogen should be used to break the first vacuum when dehydrating by the double evacuation method. However, it:",
      "answers": [
         "often contains moisture.",
         "is expensive.",
         "is toxic.",
         "can be dangerous if not used with a pressure regulator."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "can be dangerous if not used with a pressure regulator."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "A Recovery machine that uses a hermetic compressor will overheat when drawing a deep vacuum because:",
      "answers": [
         "it runs faster than other equipment.",
         "the motor needs the flow of refrigerant through the compressor to provide motor cooling.",
         "the oils used in hermetic compressors burn at lower temperatures.",
         "it has a higher compression ratio limit than other equipment."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "the motor needs the flow of refrigerant through the compressor to provide motor cooling."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "The proper charging method for blended (non-azeotropic) refrigerants (400 Series) is to use a remove the charge from the cylinder as a:",
      "answers": [
         "Vapor",
         "Liquid",
         "Superheated Vapor",
         "Subcooled Liquid"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Liquid"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "When a refrigerant trace gas becomes absolutely necessary, which of the available refrigerants should be used to identify a leak?",
      "answers": [
         "CFC-12",
         "HCFC-22",
         "HFC-407C",
         "HFC-410A"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "HCFC-22"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "After refrigerant liquid has been recovered from a system, any remaining vapor is:",
      "answers": [
         "purged to the atmosphere.",
         "isolated in the system.",
         "pumped into the system receiver.",
         "condensed by the recovery system."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "condensed by the recovery system."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "An oil sample should be taken when ___________________",
      "answers": [
         "a new filter drier has been installed.",
         "the compressor has burned-out.",
         "the unit is not cooling properly.",
         "recycled refrigerant has been added to the unit."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "the compressor has burned-out."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "In a refrigeration system with a TXV (or other type of throttling device), the component directly following the condenser is the:",
      "answers": [
         "receiver.",
         "metering device.",
         "accumulator.",
         "evaporator."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "receiver."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Recovered refrigerant may contain which of the following?",
      "answers": [
         "acids",
         "moisture",
         "oils",
         "all of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "all of the above"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "The backseating of a suction shutoff valve will close the:",
      "answers": [
         "suction line and compressor port.",
         "compressor and gauge port.",
         "gauge port.",
         "compressor port."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "gauge port."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Which repair would ALWAYS be considered \"major\" under EPA's regulations?",
      "answers": [
         "replacement of an evaporator coil.",
         "replacement of a filter-drier.",
         "replacement of a schrader valve core.",
         "replacement of a condenser fan motor."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "replacement of an evaporator coil."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "R-410A requires certified recovery and recycling machines rated for at least:",
      "answers": [
         "240 psig",
         "300 psig",
         "400 psig",
         "500 psig"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "400 psig"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "A compressor heater is used to:",
      "answers": [
         "prevent refrigerant vaporization.",
         "remove entrained water.",
         "prevent acid pitting.",
         "reduce the amount of refrigerant in the lubricating oil."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "reduce the amount of refrigerant in the lubricating oil."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Your recovery/recycling machine has R-502 refrigerant in it. You now have to recover refrigerant from a unit with R-22. What must be done before the R-22 refrigerant can be recovered/recycled?",
      "answers": [
         "nothing, as long as the recovery machine is not full",
         "change the expansion valve on the recovery machine",
         "change the filter and expansion valve on the recovery machine",
         "recover as much of the R-502 from the recovery unit as possible, change filter, and evacuate"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "recover as much of the R-502 from the recovery unit as possible, change filter, and evacuate"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "The fastest way to recover refrigerant from a system is to remove it in the __________ phase?",
      "answers": [
         "final",
         "initial",
         "liquid",
         "vapor"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "liquid"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Before using a recovery unit to remove a charge, what steps should be taken?",
      "answers": [
         "check service valve positions",
         "check the oil level in the recovery unit.",
         "evacuate recovery unit and recovery tank.",
         "all of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "all of the above"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "A deep vacuum is usually measured in:",
      "answers": [
         "psig.",
         "psia.",
         "inches of Hg.",
         "microns."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "microns."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Before transferring refrigerant to an empty cylinder?",
      "answers": [
         "The refrigerant should be chilled.",
         "The refrigerant should be mixed.",
         "The cylinder should be heated.",
         "The cylinder should be evacuated to avoid mixing air with the recovered refrigerant."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "The cylinder should be evacuated to avoid mixing air with the recovered refrigerant."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "To recover liquid refrigerant, you must connect one hose to the:",
      "answers": [
         "compressor suction valve.",
         "compressor discharge valve.",
         "liquid line.",
         "top of the condenser."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "liquid line."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "A system can be evacuated to only atmospheric pressure when:",
      "answers": [
         "the repair is major.",
         "the repair is followed by an evacuation of the appliance to the environment.",
         "leaks in the appliance make evacuation to the prescribed level unattainable.",
         "the appliance is being disposed."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "leaks in the appliance make evacuation to the prescribed level unattainable."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "The vacuum pump used to evacuate a system should be capable of pulling a vacuum of:",
      "answers": [
         "10 mm Hg.",
         "20 mm Hg.",
         "500 microns.",
         "1000 microns."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "500 microns."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "While R-410A is a high-pressure refrigerant, it can be stored in the back of your service van as long as:",
      "answers": [
         "the temperature inside the vehicle does not exceed 125F. This is the same guidance given for R-22 and other common refrigerants.",
         "the temperature inside the vehicle does not exceed 125F, but R-22 can be stored in vehicles with temperatures exceeding 125F.",
         "the temperature inside the vehicle does not exceed 155F. This is the same guidance given for R-22 and other common refrigerants.",
         "the temperature inside the vehicle does not exceed 155F, but R-22 can be stored in vehicles with temperatures exceeding 155F."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "the temperature inside the vehicle does not exceed 125F. This is the same guidance given for R-22 and other common refrigerants."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "When under a deep vacuum, the motor winding of a hermetic refrigeration compressor:",
      "answers": [
         "will be damaged if energized.",
         "must be kept warm to operate properly.",
         "will be protected by its insulation if the compressor is",
         "will overheat only if the crankcase heater is energized."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "will be damaged if energized."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Which statement is NOT true about recycling and recovery equipment manufactured after November 15, 1993?",
      "answers": [
         "It must be tested by an EPA-approved third party.",
         "It must meet vacuum standards more stringent than those met by equipment manufactured before November 15, 1993.",
         "It must be equipped with low-loss fittings.",
         "It must have an oil separator."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "It must have an oil separator."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "When a unit is opened for servicing, the ____________should always be replaced.",
      "answers": [
         "thermostat",
         "metering device",
         "crankcase heater",
         "filter-drier"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "filter-drier"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "When servicing an operating unit that has a receiver/storage tank, the:",
      "answers": [
         "compressor should be isolated off.",
         "liquid should be recovered last.",
         "refrigerant should be recovered into the receiver.",
         "gauge pressure should be achieved by venting."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "refrigerant should be recovered into the receiver."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Use __________ to remove ice from a sight glass.",
      "answers": [
         "an alcohol spray.",
         "water.",
         "R-11 refrigerant.",
         "a screwdriver or flat file."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "an alcohol spray."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "The refrigerant pressure inside an R-12 unit which is at room temperature (72F) and not operating is:",
      "answers": [
         "approximately 74 psig.",
         "approximately 154 psig.",
         "approximately 214 psig.",
         "approximately 304 psig."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "approximately 74 psig."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "You are going to service a newer residential split system air conditioner. You would expect to find the system charged with which refrigerant?",
      "answers": [
         "R-11",
         "R-12",
         "R-410A",
         "R-502"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "R-410A"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "A routine maintenance task which must be performed on refrigerant recycling machines is to _________.",
      "answers": [
         "check compressor seals",
         "change electrical fuses",
         "replace moisture sight glass",
         "change filter and compressor oil (if any)"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "change filter and compressor oil (if any)"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Refrigerant should be removed from the condenser outlet if the:",
      "answers": [
         "condenser is on the roof.",
         "compressor is inoperative.",
         "the evaporator has a leak.",
         "condenser is below the receiver."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "condenser is below the receiver."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "When evacuating a system, the use of a large vacuum pump could:",
      "answers": [
         "cause trapped oil to freeze.",
         "cause trapped refrigerant to freeze.",
         "cause trapped water to freeze.",
         "causes the valves to freeze."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "cause trapped water to freeze."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "On refrigeration units that use an open compressor; the ________________ is most likely to leak if the unit is not used for several months.",
      "answers": [
         "the suction service valve",
         "the rotating shaft seal",
         "the oil drain plug",
         "the discharge service valve"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "the rotating shaft seal"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "The primary water source for cooling the condenser of a water-cooled recovery unit is:",
      "answers": [
         "deionized water",
         "chilled water",
         "condenser water",
         "local municipal water supply"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "local municipal water supply"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "When using recovery and recycling equipment manufactured BEFORE November 15, 1993, technicians must evacuate a unit that has a normal charge of 10 pounds of CFC-500 to ___________ before disposing of the system.",
      "answers": [
         "0 psig.",
         "4 inches of Hg vacuum.",
         "10 inches of Hg vacuum.",
         "15 inches of Hg vacuum."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "4 inches of Hg vacuum."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "The evaporation temperature of R- 410A at 100 psig is about:",
      "answers": [
         "0F.",
         "30F.",
         "90F.",
         "120F."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "30F."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Non-condensables in a system cause a:",
      "answers": [
         "lower suction pressure.",
         "higher suction pressure.",
         "lower discharge pressure.",
         "higher discharge pressure."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "higher discharge pressure."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "When charging an R-410A system that uses a water-cooled condenser, you must first charge with vapor to a pressure of at least _______, before switching to liquid charging.",
      "answers": [
         "20 psig.",
         "120 psig.",
         "220 psig.",
         "320 psig."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "120 psig."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "R-410A requires recovery tanks rated for at least:",
      "answers": [
         "240 psig",
         "300 psig",
         "400 psig",
         "500 psig"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "400 psig"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "The recovery rate can be increased by:",
      "answers": [
         "packing the recovery vessel in ice.",
         "heating the recovery vessel.",
         "using a smaller recovery vessel.",
         "using a standard vacuum pump."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "packing the recovery vessel in ice."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Oil foaming usually occurs in the ________.",
      "answers": [
         "condenser",
         "evaporator",
         "compressor",
         "expansion device"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "compressor"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "During the evacuation of a system that contains large amounts of moisture it may be necessary to increase pressure in the system with ________, to counteract the freezing of the moisture.",
      "answers": [
         "hydrogen.",
         "oxygen.",
         "air.",
         "nitrogen."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "nitrogen."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Prior to replacing the condenser coil in a high pressure system, the refrigerant was recovered and stored in a refillable cylinder. The refrigerant:",
      "answers": [
         "can probably be charged back into the system.",
         "should probably be replaced with R-410A.",
         "must be reclaimed.",
         "must be destroyed."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "can probably be charged back into the system."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "The evaporation temperature of R-134a at 0 psig is:",
      "answers": [
         "-21F.",
         "-15F.",
         "-5F.",
         "-1F."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "-15F."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "When servicing a 60-ton packaged rooftop unit. The easiest way to check the type of refrigerant it uses is to:",
      "answers": [
         "use your service gauge set and a refrigerant card.",
         "ask the owner.",
         "look at the unit nameplate.",
         "determine the condenser size."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "look at the unit nameplate."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "The EPA regulations require that any appliances containing more than 50 pounds of refrigerant (except for commercial and industrial process refrigeration) must be repaired when the leak rate exceeds ______ of the charge per year.",
      "answers": [
         "5%",
         "10%",
         "20%",
         "30%"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "10%"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "The EPA regulations require that leaking commercial or industrial process refrigeration equipment must be repaired when the leak rate exceeds ______ of the charge per year.",
      "answers": [
         "5%",
         "10%",
         "20%",
         "30%"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "30%"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "You are going to service an older residential split system air conditioner. You would expect to find the system charged with which refrigerant?",
      "answers": [
         "R-11",
         "R-12",
         "R-22",
         "R-502"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "R-22"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "For what refrigerant(s) is an equipment room refrigerant monitor required under ASHRAE Standard 15?",
      "answers": [
         "R-12",
         "R-134a",
         "R-11",
         "R-123"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "R-123"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Heat Pumps that use R-134a should be leak checked with:",
      "answers": [
         "CFCs.",
         "HCFCs.",
         "compressed dry air.",
         "pressurized nitrogen."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "pressurized nitrogen."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "On a high-pressure system _________ is an indicator of a possible leak.",
      "answers": [
         "high head pressure",
         "low water temperature",
         "excessive superheat",
         "frequent purging"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "excessive superheat"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "System-dependent recovery equipment CANNOT be used when:",
      "answers": [
         "the appliance is leaking.",
         "the compressor of the appliance is operational.",
         "the ambient temperature is over 115F.",
         "the appliance contains over 15 pounds of refrigerant."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "the appliance contains over 15 pounds of refrigerant."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Moisture is removed from a system by:",
      "answers": [
         "purging the condenser.",
         "draining the oil separator.",
         "reducing water flow to the condenser.",
         "using a filter drier."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "using a filter drier."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Which component is NOT part of the low side of the system?",
      "answers": [
         "evaporator",
         "receiver",
         "suction line",
         "accumulator"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "receiver"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Soap bubble testing is used:",
      "answers": [
         "to pinpoint refrigerant leaks.",
         "only with CFCs and HCFCs.",
         "to detect water leaks.",
         "to see if the condenser or evaporator is excessively dirty."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "to pinpoint refrigerant leaks."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "Refrigerant leaves the receiver of a system as a:",
      "answers": [
         "low pressure liquid.",
         "low pressure vapor.",
         "high pressure liquid.",
         "high pressure vapor."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "high pressure liquid."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type II",
      "question": "The recovery of refrigerant from a system as a vapor only will minimize the loss of:",
      "answers": [
         "oil.",
         "water.",
         "refrigerant.",
         "all of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "oil."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Where would you place a leak detector probe to check gas leaks into the water box with water removed?",
      "answers": [
         "At the rupture disc seal.",
         "Around the vent valve.",
         "Around a test plug",
         "In the drain valve opening."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "In the drain valve opening."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Which of the following indicates air in a low-pressure system?",
      "answers": [
         "High head pressure",
         "High liquid level",
         "Low head pressure",
         "Low suction pressure"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "High head pressure"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "A hydrostatic tube test kit will:",
      "answers": [
         "determine if a tube leaks.",
         "blow all water out of tubes.",
         "remove water from a machine.",
         "vent refrigerant to the atmosphere."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "determine if a tube leaks."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "When leak testing a low-pressure centrifugal chiller with nitrogen, what is the maximum test pressure?",
      "answers": [
         "0 psig",
         "10 psig",
         "25 psig",
         "50 psig"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "10 psig"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "A rupture disc on a recovery vessel for low-pressure refrigerants relieves at:",
      "answers": [
         "5 psig",
         "10 psig",
         "15 psig",
         "20 psig."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "15 psig"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "On low-pressure chillers, moisture most frequently enters the refrigerant system through:",
      "answers": [
         "air leaks in the rupture disc assembly.",
         "tube leaks in the evaporator.",
         "leaks from areas with gaskets or fittings.",
         "leaks from the charging service valve."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "leaks from areas with gaskets or fittings."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Excessive running of a purge system on a low-pressure chiller generally indicates what condition?",
      "answers": [
         "Faulty air sensors",
         "Leaking system",
         "Ambient temperature is too high",
         "Low purge unit efficiency"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Leaking system"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Pressure relief valves can only be installed:",
      "answers": [
         "in series",
         "in parallel",
         "vertically.",
         "horizontally."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "in parallel"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Where should the discharge from a rupture disc be piped for venting?",
      "answers": [
         "To the duct system",
         "Outdoors",
         "To the evaporator",
         "Inside the machinery room"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Outdoors"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "What is the primary purpose of a purge unit on a low-pressure chiller?",
      "answers": [
         "Remove refrigerant from the system.",
         "Condense air out of the system.",
         "Condense water out of the system.",
         "Remove non-condensables from the system."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "Remove non-condensables from the system."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "A company uses a chiller that diverts 55% of its cooling capacity to one of its manufacturing lines and 45% of its cooling capacity to air condition the office spaces. Which leak rate category would this chiller be in?",
      "answers": [
         "Industrial process refrigeration",
         "Ice making refrigeration",
         "Commercial refrigeration",
         "Comfort cooling"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "Industrial process refrigeration"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Starting in 2019, what is the leak rate threshold for commercial refrigeration equipment with a full charge of 50 or more pounds of an HCFC refrigerant?",
      "answers": [
         "0.3",
         "0.2",
         "0.1",
         "0.05"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "0.2"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Where does refrigerant go after it leaves the purge unit of a low-pressure centrifugal system?",
      "answers": [
         "The evaporator",
         "The condenser",
         "The compressor intercooler",
         "The recovery service vessel"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "The evaporator"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "To determine if the system is leaking more than the allowable rate, the EPA allows the use of which one of the following methods to determine the full charge?",
      "answers": [
         "Use of the calculations based on power consumption, in kWh.",
         "Use of the calculations based on compressor horsepower.",
         "Use of calculations based on component and pipe sizes.",
         "Use of the calculations based on the BTU capacity of the system."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "Use of calculations based on component and pipe sizes."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "ASHRAE Standard 15-2013 requires the use of room sensors and alarms to detect:",
      "answers": [
         "refrigerant leaks.",
         "high levels of ozone.",
         "refrigerant contamination.",
         "excessive oxygen levels."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "refrigerant leaks."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Why do chillers using low-pressure refrigerants require purge units?",
      "answers": [
         "These systems require the removal of contaminated refrigerant",
         "These systems operate below atmospheric pressure",
         "Purge units remove refrigerant from the oil sump",
         "These systems require the removal of condensables from the chiller"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "These systems operate below atmospheric pressure"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Why should the oil be removed from a low-pressure system at 130\u00b0F?",
      "answers": [
         "130\u00b0F is the normal operating temperature for oil in a low-pressure system.",
         "Less refrigerant will be contained in the oil the higher temperature.",
         "Warmer oil has a lower viscosity and flows more easily.",
         "It shows that the heater is working."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Less refrigerant will be contained in the oil the higher temperature."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "The EPA's leak repair requirements apply to appliances with a charge size of",
      "answers": [
         "5 pounds or less.",
         "30 pounds or greater.",
         "50 pounds or greater.",
         "100 pounds or greater."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "50 pounds or greater."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "What is meant by the term \"high efficiency purge unit?\"",
      "answers": [
         "Purge units that discharge a high percentage of refrigerant with the air they remove.",
         "Purge units that discharge a low percentage of refrigerant with the air they remove.",
         "Purge units that consume less than 5 watts of electrical power.",
         "Purge units which contain less than 50 lbs of refrigerant."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Purge units that discharge a low percentage of refrigerant with the air they remove."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "During evacuation with large amounts of moisture it may be necessary to increase pressure to counteract freezing with gas such as:",
      "answers": [
         "R-410A",
         "R-22",
         "Air",
         "Nitrogen"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "Nitrogen"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "A typical setting for the high pressure cut-out control on a recovery unit used for evacuating the refrigerant from a low-pressure chiller is:",
      "answers": [
         "2 psig.",
         "5 psig.",
         "10 psig.",
         "15 psig."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "10 psig."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "A chiller with a charge of 200 pounds of an ozone-depleting refrigerant has passed the initial verification leak test. When must a follow-up verification test be conducted?",
      "answers": [
         "The same day",
         "The next day",
         "Within 10 days",
         "Within 30 days"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "Within 10 days"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Where is the rupture disc located on a centrifugal chiller?",
      "answers": [
         "Condenser",
         "Evaporator",
         "Liquid line",
         "Economizer"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Evaporator"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Where is refrigerant added to a centrifugal machine?",
      "answers": [
         "Condenser",
         "Evaporator",
         "Liquid line",
         "Economizer"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Evaporator"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "After all the liquid has been removed from an average 350-ton, low-pressure appliance, approximately how much vapor refrigerant remains in the system?",
      "answers": [
         "100 pounds",
         "150 pounds",
         "350 pounds",
         "45 pounds"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "100 pounds"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "A low-pressure chiller used for comfort cooling must be repaired if it has an annual leak rate of ____ of the total charge.",
      "answers": [
         "10%",
         "20%",
         "30%",
         "50%"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "10%"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "If a strong odor is detected during the recovery process,",
      "answers": [
         "the refrigerant is most likely R-717 (Ammonia).",
         "the purge unit on the condenser has opened.",
         "a compressor burn-out may have occurred.",
         "it is a good indicator that R-123 is the refrigerant being recovered."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "a compressor burn-out may have occurred."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Where is refrigerant added to a low-pressure system during the charging process?",
      "answers": [
         "The access valve on the purge unit entering the condenser.",
         "The lowest access point on the system such as the condenser charging valve.",
         "The highest access point on the system such as the evaporator inlet valve.",
         "The lowest access point on the system such as the evaporator charging valve."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "The lowest access point on the system such as the evaporator charging valve."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "When charging a low-pressure system, refrigerant should be introduced to the system as a vapor to raise the system's saturation temperature to a minimum of;",
      "answers": [
         "0 degrees.",
         "36 degrees.",
         "40 degrees.",
         "70 degrees."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "36 degrees."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "During evacuation of systems with large amounts of water, it may be necessary to;",
      "answers": [
         "increase pressure by introducing nitrogen to counteract freezing.",
         "purge the condenser by removing nitrogen to encourage freezing.",
         "drain the compressor by removing nitrogen to encourage freezing.",
         "decrease pressure by introducing nitrogen to counteract freezing."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "increase pressure by introducing nitrogen to counteract freezing."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Because a low-pressure system operates below atmospheric pressure (in a vacuum),",
      "answers": [
         "the system is unlikely to have air and moisture enter the system.",
         "leaks in gaskets or fittings will cause air and moisture to enter the system.",
         "leaks in the gaskets or fittings will cause substantial refrigerant leaks.",
         "leaks in the gaskets or fittings will cause oil clogging at the condenser."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "leaks in gaskets or fittings will cause air and moisture to enter the system."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "In a low-pressure chiller, air and other non-condensables collect at the;",
      "answers": [
         "bottom of the compressor.",
         "top section of the condenser.",
         "bottom of the evaporator.",
         "header before the metering device."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "top section of the condenser."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "The most efficient method of leak checking a charged low-pressure refrigeration unit is to;",
      "answers": [
         "pressurize the system using controlled hot water or heater blankets.",
         "pull a 500-micron vacuum and hold for at least 12 minutes.",
         "pull a 20-inch vacuum and hold for at least 24 hours.",
         "pull a 29.9-inch vacuum and hold for at least 24 hours."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "pressurize the system using controlled hot water or heater blankets."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "The Standard for machine room safety is;",
      "answers": [
         "ASHRAE-15",
         "ASHRAE-34",
         "AHRI-740",
         "EPA-740"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "ASHRAE-15"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "When installing more than one, pressure relief valves must be installed;",
      "answers": [
         "in series with each other.",
         "in parallel with each other.",
         "in the system's suction line.",
         "on top of compressor head."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "in parallel with each other."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "The EPA-required evacuation level for recovery or recycling equipment used on low-pressure systems is",
      "answers": [
         "15 inches Hg.",
         "20 inches Hg.",
         "25 mm of Hg absolute.",
         "30 inches Hg absolute."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "25 mm of Hg absolute."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "When pressurizing a low-pressure system for leak-detection purposes, do not exceed",
      "answers": [
         "5 psig",
         "10 psig",
         "15 psig",
         "20 psig"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "10 psig"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "What type of equipment can be worked on with Type III certification?",
      "answers": [
         "High-pressure",
         "Medium-pressure",
         "Low-pressure",
         "Vacuum pressure"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "Low-pressure"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "How long would an equipment owner or operator have to retrofit or retire an appliance that has exceeded the threshold leak rate if the replacement appliance uses 50 pounds or more of an exempt refrigerant?",
      "answers": [
         "24 months.",
         "18 months.",
         "12 months.",
         "3 months."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "18 months."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Which of the following best describes the refrigerant recovery process from an R-123 system?",
      "answers": [
         "Start with vapor removal and then switch over to liquid recovery.",
         "Start with liquid removal and then switch over to vapor recovery.",
         "Run the compressor and only recover refrigerant in the liquid state.",
         "Run the compressor and only recover refrigerant in the vapor state."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Start with liquid removal and then switch over to vapor recovery."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "What can be used to pressurize a chiller system before opening the system for a non-major repair?",
      "answers": [
         "Controlled hot water",
         "Nitrogen",
         "R-409A",
         "Compressed air"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "Controlled hot water"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "The rupture disk on a low-pressure chiller has a burst pressure of;",
      "answers": [
         "5 psig",
         "10 psig",
         "15 psig",
         "20 psig"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "15 psig"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Where is the purge unit located in a low-pressure system?",
      "answers": [
         "The top of the condenser.",
         "In the lowest location.",
         "Above the shell.",
         "Before the oil separator."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "The top of the condenser."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "To repair a chiller operating with R-22, the technician;",
      "answers": [
         "does not need a certification.",
         "must have a Type I certification.",
         "must have a Type II certification.",
         "must have a Type III certification."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "must have a Type II certification."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Which of the following refrigerants has a safety classification of B-1",
      "answers": [
         "CFC-12 (R-12)",
         "HFC-134a (R-134a)",
         "HCFC-123 (R-123)",
         "CFC-11 (R-11)"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "HCFC-123 (R-123)"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Which organization establishes the refrigerant safety group standard?",
      "answers": [
         "AHRI",
         "UL",
         "ASHRAE",
         "ASE"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "ASHRAE"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "When leak testing a low-pressure chiller, the maximum pressure to use is;",
      "answers": [
         "5 psig",
         "10 psig",
         "15 psig",
         "20 psig"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "10 psig"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "The owner must keep records of refrigerant added to a low-pressure system during service and maintenance if the system charge is;",
      "answers": [
         "25 pounds or greater.",
         "50 pounds or greater.",
         "100 pounds or greater.",
         "150 pounds or greater."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "50 pounds or greater."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Under ASHRAE Standard 34, R-134a is classified as;",
      "answers": [
         "A1",
         "A2",
         "B1",
         "B2"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "A1"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "A typical setting for the high pressure cut-out control on a recovery unit used for evacuating the refrigerant from a low pressure chiller is:",
      "answers": [
         "2 psig.",
         "5 psig.",
         "10 psig.",
         "15 psig."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "10 psig."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "A charged low pressure refrigeration system can be efficiently leak checked by:",
      "answers": [
         "adding compressed air, since it will be removed from the system by the Purging unit.",
         "operating the purge system.",
         "adding HCFC-22.",
         "raising system pressure by heating with circulated hot water or heating blankets."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "raising system pressure by heating with circulated hot water or heating blankets."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "The existence of air in a low pressure system, causes __________.",
      "answers": [
         "low head pressure.",
         "low suction pressure.",
         "high head pressure.",
         "high liquid level."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "high head pressure."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Which safety precaution should be adhered to for low pressure systems?",
      "answers": [
         "Do not siphon refrigerant by mouth.",
         "Avoid spilling liquid refrigerant on the skin.",
         "Use gloves and safety goggles when working with liquid refrigerant.",
         "all of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "all of the above"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Refrigerant-11 at 14.7 PSIA will boil at about:",
      "answers": [
         "60.3F.",
         "74.5F.",
         "79.7F.",
         "80.2F."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "74.5F."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "When there is excessive moisture collecting in the purge unit of a low pressure refrigeration system, this indicates that the __________.",
      "answers": [
         "the system was charged with contaminated refrigerant.",
         "the condenser or chiller barrel tubes are leaking.",
         "the purge unit is not operating properly.",
         "the purge unit needs adjustment."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "the condenser or chiller barrel tubes are leaking."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "ASHRAE Standard 15 - 1994 requires equipment room refrigerant sensors for what safety group classification?",
      "answers": [
         "A1",
         "B2",
         "A2",
         "All refrigerant safety groups"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "All refrigerant safety groups"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "When recharging a refrigeration system with R-11, what vapor pressure is necessary in the shells before charging with liquid?",
      "answers": [
         "21.1\" Hg vacuum",
         "19.7\" Hg vacuum",
         "18.1\" Hg vacuum",
         "16.9\" Hg vacuum"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "16.9\" Hg vacuum"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "After reaching the required recovery vacuum on a chiller, you should:",
      "answers": [
         "Immediately disconnect the recycling or recovery equipment and open the system for service.",
         "Wait for at least a few minutes to see if the system pressure rises, indicating that there is still refrigerant in liquid form or in the oil.",
         "Immediately break the vacuum with nitrogen and open the system for service.",
         "Immediately pressurize the system with nitrogen and perform a leak check."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Wait for at least a few minutes to see if the system pressure rises, indicating that there is still refrigerant in liquid form or in the oil."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "A hydrostatic tube test kit is used to:",
      "answers": [
         "blow all water from the tubes.",
         "remove any water from the machine.",
         "vent refrigerant.",
         "determine if a tube leaks."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "determine if a tube leaks."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "When charging a chiller, refrigerant vapor is introduced into the system before charging with liquid. This is because:",
      "answers": [
         "Vapor charging increases pressure slowly, preventing failure of the rupture disk.",
         "Vapor charging is faster than liquid charging.",
         "Liquid charging is more difficult to control than vapor charging.",
         "Liquid charged into a deep vacuum will cause the refrigerant to boil and may lower temperatures enough to freeze the water in the tubes."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "Liquid charged into a deep vacuum will cause the refrigerant to boil and may lower temperatures enough to freeze the water in the tubes."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "When evacuating a system, the use of too large a vacuum pump can cause:",
      "answers": [
         "trapped water to freeze.",
         "trapped oil to freeze.",
         "trapped refrigerant to freeze.",
         "valves to freeze."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "trapped water to freeze."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "On a low-pressure chiller with an open-type compressor, the ________________ is very susceptible to leaks.",
      "answers": [
         "chiller tubes",
         "shaft seal",
         "charging connections",
         "shaft bearings"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "shaft seal"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "What steps may be taken to prevent air accumulation into an idle low pressure refrigeration system?",
      "answers": [
         "Leave the purge unit on-line at all times.",
         "System pressure should be maintained slightly above atmospheric.",
         "Open the air vents on the condenser.",
         "Intermittently operate the system with no load."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "System pressure should be maintained slightly above atmospheric."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Commercial and industrial process refrigeration systems must be repaired when the leak rate exceeds ______ percent of the charge per year.",
      "answers": [
         "5%",
         "10%",
         "20%",
         "30%"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "30%"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "When recovering vapor from a low pressure refrigeration system the:",
      "answers": [
         "water pumps should be on, and the recovery compressor should be off.",
         "system water pumps should be on, the recovery compressor should be on, and the recovery condenser water should be off.",
         "system water pumps, the recovery compressor, and the recovery condenser water should all be on.",
         "system water pumps should be off, and the recovery compressor should be on."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "system water pumps, the recovery compressor, and the recovery condenser water should all be on."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Where does refrigerant go after it leaves the purge unit of a low pressure centrifugal system?",
      "answers": [
         "the evaporator",
         "the condenser",
         "the compressor intercooler",
         "the recovery service vessel"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "the evaporator"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "The purge unit takes its suction from the:",
      "answers": [
         "top of the condenser.",
         "compressor oil sump.",
         "top of the evaporator.",
         "suction elbow."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "top of the condenser."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Which of the following repairs would ALWAYS be considered \"major\" under EPA's regulations?",
      "answers": [
         "replacement of an evaporator coil",
         "replacement of a filter-drier",
         "replacement of a switch",
         "replacement of a purge unit"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "replacement of an evaporator coil"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Charging refrigerant liquid into a refrigeration system when it is under a 29 inch Hg vacuum can cause the:",
      "answers": [
         "liquid to absorb excess moisture.",
         "purge unit to operate.",
         "system water to freeze.",
         "refrigerant liquid to freeze."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "system water to freeze."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "According to the EPA, there is approximately _______ refrigerant vapor left in an average 350 ton R- 11 chiller at 0 psig pressure once all the R-11 liquid has been removed?",
      "answers": [
         "none",
         "10 lbs.",
         "20 lbs.",
         "100 lbs."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "100 lbs."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "An oil sample should be taken when __________________.",
      "answers": [
         "a new filter drier has been installed.",
         "there has been a compressor burnout.",
         "the unit is not cooling properly.",
         "recycled refrigerant has been added to the unit."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "there has been a compressor burnout."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Both CFC-11 and HCFC-123 chillers require purge units because:",
      "answers": [
         "the purge units remove moisture",
         "the system operates below atmospheric pressure",
         "purge units remove refrigerant from the oil sump",
         "purge units remove CFCs from the chiller"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "the system operates below atmospheric pressure"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Refrigerant recovery typically starts with_______ because it is faster.",
      "answers": [
         "vapor recovery",
         "liquid recovery",
         "combined vapor and liquid recovery.",
         "oil separation."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "liquid recovery"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Under EPA's regulations, __________________ is used to pressurize a low-pressure chiller for the purpose of opening the system for a non-major repair?",
      "answers": [
         "adding nitrogen",
         "warming the refrigerant",
         "adding compressed air",
         "adding carbon dioxide"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "warming the refrigerant"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "The primary water source for a recovery unit condensing coil is ______.",
      "answers": [
         "chilled water",
         "condenser water",
         "local municipal water supply",
         "deionized water"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "local municipal water supply"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Which statement is NOT true of recycling and recovery equipment manufactured after November 15, 1993?",
      "answers": [
         "It must be tested by an EPA-approved third party.",
         "It must meet vacuum standards more stringent than those met by equipment manufactured before November 15, 1993.",
         "It must be equipped with low-loss fittings.",
         "It must be able to handle more than one refrigerant."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "It must be able to handle more than one refrigerant."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "A system does not have to be evacuated all the way to the required level when:",
      "answers": [
         "the repair is major.",
         "the repair is followed by an evacuation of the appliance to the environment.",
         "the appliance is being disposed.",
         "leaks in the appliance make evacuation to the prescribed level unattainable."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "leaks in the appliance make evacuation to the prescribed level unattainable."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Which action listed below is the proper method to reduce refrigerant loss from a purge unit on a CFC-11 chiller?",
      "answers": [
         "leak test and repair the chiller",
         "seal the purge-unit discharge",
         "pipe purge-unit back into the low side",
         "pipe purge-unit into recovery unit"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "leak test and repair the chiller"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Identify the pressure corresponding to 32F for R-123:",
      "answers": [
         "23 inches of Hg vacuum.",
         "20 inches of Hg vacuum.",
         "17 inches of Hg vacuum.",
         "11 inches of Hg vacuum."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "20 inches of Hg vacuum."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "What precaution should be taken prior to recovering refrigerant from a chiller suspected of having tube leaks",
      "answers": [
         "Drain the water sides of the evaporator and condenser.",
         "Run the circulating pumps.",
         "Be certain the purge unit is operating.",
         "Open the condenser vents."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "Drain the water sides of the evaporator and condenser."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Pressure relief valves must never be:",
      "answers": [
         "installed in series.",
         "installed in parallel.",
         "installed vertically.",
         "installed horizontally."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "installed in series."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "If you are going to removing oil from a low pressure system, you should heat the oil because:",
      "answers": [
         "you can warm your hands on the container.",
         "less refrigerant will be contained in the oil at the higher temperature.",
         "warmer oil has a lower viscosity and flows more easily.",
         "it shows that the heater is working."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "less refrigerant will be contained in the oil at the higher temperature."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "After recovering the liquid refrigerant you must:",
      "answers": [
         "recover the vapor refrigerant",
         "pressurize system with nitrogen",
         "remove the oil from the system",
         "solvent-flush the entire system"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "recover the vapor refrigerant"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "EPA regulations require that any appliances containing more than 50 pounds of refrigerant (except for commercial and industrial process refrigeration) must be repaired when the leak rate exceeds ______ of the charge per year.",
      "answers": [
         "5%",
         "10%",
         "20%",
         "30%"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "10%"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "If you are using a recovery machine manufactured BEFORE November 15, 1993, you must evacuate any low-pressure appliance to ________ before making a major repair:",
      "answers": [
         "0 psig.",
         "15 inches of Hg vacuum.",
         "25 inches of Hg vacuum.",
         "25 mm of Hg absolute."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "25 mm of Hg absolute."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "On low pressure chillers, moisture typically enters the refrigerant system through:",
      "answers": [
         "air leaks in the rupture disc assembly.",
         "tube leaks.",
         "air leaks from areas with gaskets or fittings.",
         "air leaks from the charging valve."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "air leaks from areas with gaskets or fittings."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Refrigerant-11 at a pressure of 17 inches Hg vacuum has a saturation temperature of:",
      "answers": [
         "30F.",
         "35F.",
         "40F.",
         "44F."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "35F."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "The lowest access point on a low pressure centrifugal air-conditioning unit is the:",
      "answers": [
         "the evaporator charging valve",
         "the condenser service valve",
         "the compressor cooler jacket",
         "the purge unit exhaust port"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "the evaporator charging valve"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "A rupture disc on a recovery vessel for low pressure refrigerants relieves at:",
      "answers": [
         "5 psig.",
         "10 psig.",
         "15 psig.",
         "20 psig."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "15 psig."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "According to ASHRAE Guideline 3-1996, if the pressure in a system rises from 1 mm Hg to a level above ______ during a standing vacuum test, the system should be checked for leaks.",
      "answers": [
         "1.5 mm Hg",
         "2.0 mm Hg",
         "2.5 mm Hg",
         "3.0 mm Hg"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "2.5 mm Hg"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "During chiller evacuation, water is circulated to:",
      "answers": [
         "speed up the recovery process.",
         "prevent loss of refrigerant to the atmosphere.",
         "prevent freezing of the water.",
         "maintain constant refrigerant pressure."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "prevent freezing of the water."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "When charging an R-410A water chiller, you must first charge with vapor to a pressure of at least _______, before switching to liquid charging.",
      "answers": [
         "20 psig.",
         "120 psig.",
         "220 psig.",
         "320 psig."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "120 psig."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "If you leak test a low pressure chiller with nitrogen in excess of 10 psig you could cause the _____________ to fail.",
      "answers": [
         "condenser tubes",
         "purge unit shells",
         "evaporator tubes",
         "rupture disc"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "rupture disc"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "ASHRAE Standard 15 - 1994 requires that each machinery room must activate an alarm and mechanical ventilation before refrigerant concentrations exceed:",
      "answers": [
         "the EEL (Emergency Exposure Limit).",
         "the TLV-TWA (Threshold Limit Value - Time Weighted Average).",
         "the UTL (Upper Threshold Limit).",
         "the COP (Coefficient of Performance)."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "the TLV-TWA (Threshold Limit Value - Time Weighted Average)."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Which repair WOULD NOT fall under the EPA definition for \"MAJOR MAINTENANCE, SERVICE, OR REPAIR\"?>",
      "answers": [
         "replacing an oil filter",
         "replacing the compressor",
         "re-tubing a condenser",
         "replacing a fin and tube forced air evaporator coil"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "replacing an oil filter"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Refrigerant is added to a centrifugal machine through the:",
      "answers": [
         "float valve.",
         "compressor service valve.",
         "condenser charging valve.",
         "evaporator charging valve."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "evaporator charging valve."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "What is meant by the term \"high efficiency purge unit?\"",
      "answers": [
         "Those purge units which discharge a high percentage of refrigerant with the air which they remove.",
         "Those purge units which discharge a low percentage of refrigerant with the air which they remove.",
         "Those purge units which draw very little electrical power.",
         "None of the above."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "Those purge units which discharge a low percentage of refrigerant with the air which they remove."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "The PRIMARY purpose of a purge unit on a CFC-11 chiller is to:",
      "answers": [
         "remove CFCs from the system.",
         "condense air out of the system.",
         "condense water out of the system.",
         "remove non-condensables from the system."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "remove non-condensables from the system."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "If you are using a recovery machine manufactured AFTER November 15, 1993, you must evacuate any low- pressure appliance to ________ before making a major repair:",
      "answers": [
         "0 psig.",
         "15 inches of Hg vacuum.",
         "25 inches of Hg vacuum.",
         "25 mm of Hg absolute."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "25 mm of Hg absolute."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "If you suspect a leak in the water box of a chiller, you should place the leak detector probe ________________________, and sniff for refrigerants.",
      "answers": [
         "at the rupture disc",
         "through the vent valve",
         "through a test plug",
         "through a drain valve"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "through a drain valve"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "To determine how much vapor to charge into an evacuated chiller, you should charge with vapor until ____________________.",
      "answers": [
         "the system pressure corresponds to a refrigerant saturation temperature of 36F.",
         "the recovery unit liquid level drops.",
         "you have charged with vapor for 15 minutes.",
         "the recovery unit pressure drops."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "the system pressure corresponds to a refrigerant saturation temperature of 36F."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "ASHRAE Standard 15 - 1994 requires the use of room sensors and alarms to detect:",
      "answers": [
         "refrigerant leaks.",
         "high levels of ozone.",
         "refrigerant contamination.",
         "excessive oxygen levels."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "refrigerant leaks."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "The discharge from a rupture disc should be piped ____________ for venting?",
      "answers": [
         "outdoors",
         "inside the machinery room",
         "to the evaporator",
         "to the duct system"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "outdoors"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "A centrifugal chiller's rupture disk is connected to the chiller's",
      "answers": [
         "condenser.",
         "evaporator.",
         "liquid line.",
         "economizer."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "evaporator."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "To remove ice from sight glasses or viewing glasses, use:",
      "answers": [
         "R-11 refrigerant.",
         "an alcohol spray.",
         "water.",
         "a screwdriver or flat file."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "an alcohol spray."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "The maximum test pressure for leak testing a low pressure centrifugal is:",
      "answers": [
         "0 psig",
         "10 psig",
         "25 psig",
         "50 psig"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 1,
      "correct_answer": "10 psig"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "According to ASHRAE Standard 34, what is the safety classification of R-123?",
      "answers": [
         "A1",
         "A2",
         "B1",
         "B2"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "B1"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "Excessive running of a purge system on a low pressure chiller generally indicates that the:",
      "answers": [
         "air sensors are faulty.",
         "ambient temperature is too high.",
         "efficiency of the purge unit is too low.",
         "system is leaking."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 3,
      "correct_answer": "system is leaking."
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "The typical design burst pressure for a rupture disk on a low pressure centrifugal air-conditioning system is set at ________,",
      "answers": [
         "7 psi",
         "10 psi",
         "15 psi",
         "28 psi"
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 2,
      "correct_answer": "15 psi"
   },
   {
      "type": "Type III",
      "question": "During the evacuation of a system containing large amounts of moisture, you can prevent freezing of this moisture by increasing the pressure with _______ gas,",
      "answers": [
         "nitrogen.",
         "R-22.",
         "air.",
         "oxygen."
      ],
      "correct_answer_offset": 0,
      "correct_answer": "nitrogen."
   }
];